Privacy
=======

*   Privacy

#### Get full control to manage your privacy

Manage Your Cookie Settings

Privacy notice
--------------

At Vodafone your privacy is taken seriously and dealt with responsibly. Read the privacy notice to know the different ways in which we use and manage your personal information.

### About our Privacy Notice

Changes to our privacy notice

This Privacy Notice gets updated from time to time; whenever we make a material change, we’ll post this on our website and let you know.

We have revised our privacy notice as we are introducing some new features and ways of working. The main changes are outlined below.

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Version | Section | Changes | Date |
| 1.0 | All | First Draft | 23 May 2018 |
| 1.1 | How we use your information | Updated text on analytics | 28 September 2020 |
| 1.2 | How long we keep your personal information | Update retention periods | 19 January 2024 |
| 1.3 | How we use your information | Updated text on analytics to include ‘customer profile’ | 19 January 2024 |
| 2.0 | All | Structural and content changes in the privacy notice template. | 14 October 2024 |
| 2.1 | Profiling, Fraud Management and Security | Updated What data is used? in Fraud Prevention & Security to include 'Credential information' | 4 February 2025 |
| 2.2 | How we use your personal information and our lawful basis to do so | Referenced use of automated tools | 4 July 2025 |
| 2.3 | To comply with mandatory legal obligation | Nuisance Communications purposes | 13 Jan 2026 |

Last updated: 13 Jan 2026

#### How to use this privacy notice

In this notice, we explain how we collect, use, share and protect your personal information when you use our products and services and our website.

#### Who we are

We are Vodafone Ireland and we are a member of the Vodafone Group. If you go to [where Vodafone operates globally](http://www.vodafone.com/content/index/about/where.html) you can find links to all of the Vodafone operating companies that are part of the Vodafone Group.

In this privacy notice:

*   “Vodafone/we/us/our” means Vodafone Ireland;
    
*   “third party” means someone who is not you or us;
    
*   “partner organisation” means external third party business entity that provides value-added services; and
    
*   “Vodafone Group” means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital.

Our registered office is Mountainview, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, Ireland. We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967. Our main switchboard is (01) 2037000 or you can email us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

#### How to contact us

Your opinion matters to us – if you have any questions about our privacy notice, you can email us at: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or you can contact our Customer Care team on 1907.

You may contact our Data Protection Officer by email at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or in writing to Mountainview, Leopardstown, Dublin 18.

#### Our principles

Vodafone is committed to respecting your privacy. We take privacy, security, and complying with data protection and privacy laws seriously.

We have set out our core [Privacy Commitments](http://www.vodafone.com/content/index/about/privacy.html) in our Privacy Centre. We aim to put these commitments at the heart of everything we do.

### Personal information we collect about you

Directly from you

The information we collect about you and how we collect it can vary depending on the products and services that you use and subscribe to, how you have used the products and services, how you have interacted with Vodafone, even if you aren’t a customer, or what we have obtained from a third party.

We will collect your personal information when you, for example:

*   sign up to any of our products or services;
    
*   use our network or other Vodafone products or services;
    
*   contact us through various channels for support or ask for information about products or services;
    
*   visit or browse our website; and
    
*   if you are a non-Vodafone customer and contact a Vodafone customer or a Vodafone customer care team.

From third parties

Information collected not directly from you:

*   Information we obtain from other sources, such as credit agencies, fraud-prevention agencies, and from other data providers. This includes demographic data, interest-based data, and internet browsing behaviour.

The types of information we may have, where applicable:

1.  Contact details: Such as your name, address, phone and/or mobile number and email address;
    
2.  Financial details: Such as your credit or debit card information, information about your bank account and other banking information – for example, you’ll have to give us this information when you open an account with us. We’ll collect the data necessary to process a payment whenever you make a purchase;
    
3.  Your traffic data: Every time you use your mobile phone, a record is kept. This includes the number you called or sent an SMS or MMS to, the length, date and time of that call, SMS or MMS, the amount of data you are using and your approximate location at the time that the communication takes place (based on the location of the nearest cell that you sent that call or message from). The same is also recorded every time you receive an incoming call or message. This is data we see as part of providing you with connectivity; we don’t, however, keep a record of the content of your calls or messages.
    
4.  Information about your device or connectivity: such as IP address, IMEI and MSISDN.
    
5.  Your location data: This can be precise where it uses Global Positioning System (GPS) data or by identifying nearby mobile phone masts and Wi-Fi hotspots and you enable location-based services or features. Or less precise where, for example, a location is derived from your IP address or data such as a post code or name of a town or city;
    
6.  Your contact with us: Such as a note or recording of a call you make to one of our contact centres, a Live Chat, an email or letter sent, or other records of any contact with us;
    
7.  Your account information: Such as your date of birth, gender, dates of payment owed or received, subscriptions you use, account numbers or other information related to your account or included in My Vodafone;
    
8.  Credential information: We’ll collect passwords, hints, and similar security information used for authentication and access to accounts and services;
    
9.  Your preferences: for products, services and lifestyle activities when you tell us what they are, or we assume what they are, based on how you use the products and services;
    
10.  Cookies: See the [Cookie Policy](#cookies) for details on what we collect using cookies, web beacons and other technologies, including advertising data;
     
11.  Your browsing history: If you have given your permission, Vodafone collects the categories of website you have browsed on your mobile, device or PC, for example Sports, Music or News. However, we don’t have a history of the sites you browse, as this is limited for a short period of time to enable the connection to be made. We use these interests to send you personalised marketing or show you personalised advertising. You can opt out of advertising and manage how we use cookies through the Cookie Settings which can be accessed via our [Cookies Policy](#cookies) or, in the case of marketing, your [Privacy Settings](#privacysettings).
     
12.  Information about how you use our products and services: Such as the level of service that you receive – for example, network or service faults and other events that may affect our network services or other services; or your viewing history if you use our VTV product for example.
     
13.  Details of your use of the specific services or products: for example CIOT devices or VTV. You can refer to the specific privacy supplement for each product/service for more information on the data processed.

### How we use your personal information and our lawful basis to do so

We will use your personal information for a number of purposes, ranging from enabling us to provide you with the products or services you have requested to ensuring we are keeping these secure from fraud.

We may use Artificial Intelligence (A.I.) to help us provide you with a requested product or service. If we use A.I. we will do so responsibly, and where necessary we will disclose that the content is generated by A.I.

We may also use automated tools to assist with activities such as reconciling customer accounts and improving service efficiency. These tools do not make decisions that affect your rights or obligations.

Whenever we use your personal information, we do so based on a specific lawful basis under data protection law listed below:

1.  The performance of your contract or to enter into the contract and to take action on your requests for example, so you can make calls and texts, and browse the internet on your phone, we process things like the numbers you dial, how much data you’re using and when you’re doing it so we can provide connectivity. This also enables us to generate your bill, based on your usage. We also may conduct credit checks when you apply for a product or service, which is operated on a bill pay basis to verify your suitability for entry into such a contract.
    
2.  Legitimate interests of Vodafone for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, direct marketing, and improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our legitimate interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, go to Your Rights at the end of this section.
    
3.  Compliance with a mandatory legal obligation including for example accounting and tax requirements, which are subject to strict internal policies (such as retention periods), procedures.
    
4.  Consent where you have provided it by your own free will. Consent may be withdrawn at any time. See Your Rights at the end of this section for more information on how to do this.

Please see the table below for more information.

Below you can find an overview of the categories of personal information we process about you, the purposes for which we process that personal information and the lawful basis upon which we rely to conduct that processing.

Third parties that we work with

We are not in the business of selling your data, we only share your data with suppliers who help us to provide services.

When you’ve purchased Vodafone products and services using a third party or partner organisation, we often need to exchange information with them as part of managing that relationship and your account – for example, to be able to identify your order and be able to pay them.

If we have a contract with a service provider or contractor to provide us with services or provide a service on our behalf, they may have access to your personal information. We don’t authorise them to use or disclose your personal information received from us except in connection with providing their services.

We collect and combine information in order to monitor your use of products and services, and that of our other customers, as well as to help us to improve the quality of our products and services. We provide this information to third parties (for example, to content providers and advertisers), but any such third-party reporting shall not include information which may identify an individual customer.

Mergers and Acquisitions

If we reorganised or merged with or divested part of our business to another organisation, we may need to provide your information to that other organisation or their advisers or receive personal information from that other organisation.

Third party devices that you connect your SIM with

You may connect your SIM with a number of third-party devices, either manually with a SIM card or electronically through our One Number product. These may include mobile phone devices or connected devices such as smart speakers or smartwatches. When you connect your SIM with these devices, those third parties may record your SIM details or your interaction with the network and provide that information to Vodafone for purposes of validating your eligibility for the OneNumber product offering. Those third-party device manufacturers will process your personal data in accordance with their requirements and we recommend that you read their privacy notices / policies before choosing to connect your sim to their devices.

Third party products that you buy through your Vodafone account

Where you buy a third-party product or service through your Vodafone account (such as Charge to Bill for mobile), the contract for it is with the party selling that product or service. Vodafone is only charging the amount directly to your bill as part of its arrangements with the seller. As part of this, you’re agreeing that Vodafone may pass certain personal information to the seller to complete your purchase with them.

The seller’s terms and conditions, privacy and cookies policies will apply to how it uses your personal information – please read them carefully.

### To provide you with your service

It is necessary for us to process your personal information to enable us to provide you with your service. By service we mean any services or products that you buy or use such as broadband, mobiles, use of our apps or smart tech products.

| How is your information used? | What data is used? | Lawful basis |
| --- | --- | --- |
| To process your order and provide you with your products and services<br><br>• To process orders for the products and services you’ve bought from us, and keep you updated with the progress of your order.<br><br>• To provide the relevant products or services to you. This includes other services not included in your agreement with us, services that use information about where you are, and to contact you with messages about changes to the products or services.<br><br>• Where you’ve purchased Vodafone products and services using a third party or partner organisation, we often need to exchange information with them as part of managing that relationship and your account – for example, to be able to identify your order and be able to pay them. | Contact details<br><br>Account information<br><br>Financial details | Performance of your contract |
| Billing and Customer Care<br><br>• To bill you for using our products and services, or to take the appropriate amount of credit from you;<br><br>• To contact you if the billing information you provided us with is about to expire or we’re not able to take payment;<br><br>• To respond to any questions or concerns you may have about our network, products or services. | Account information<br><br>Financial details<br><br>Your contact with us | Performance of your contract |
| Service messages<br><br>• We will contact you with customer service messages to keep you updated with current information about products and services you’ve purchased. For example, changes to our terms and conditions, price plan and data use, upgrades you might be entitled to, roaming or service interruptions. | Contact details<br><br>Account information | Performance of your contract |
| Complaint handling purposes<br><br>• Regarding the service provided by and under contract with Vodafone<br><br>NB: Vodafone may also handle your complaint in compliance with mandatory legal obligation as outlined in the ‘To comply with mandatory legal obligation’ section | Account information<br><br>Customer Relationship Management data | Performance of your contract |

### To improve our service

We collect information about your use of our products and services on an aggregated or anonymous basis in order to help us manage and improve the services we offer to everyone.

| How is your information used? | What data is used? | Lawful basis |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Improving and innovating our products and services<br><br>• Where possible or practicable, we anonymise, de-identify or aggregate information in order to improve the service we offer to everyone. None of these analytics are linked back to you in any way. However, if the purpose requires the data to be processed in identifiable form, we will only do so if we have your consent. | Anonymised/<br><br>aggregated:<br><br>Financial details<br><br>Traffic data | Consent |
| Improving and innovating our products and services through third parties<br><br>• We collect and combine information in order to monitor your use of products and services, and that of our other customers, as well as to help us to improve the quality of our products and services. We provide this information to third parties (for example, to content providers and advertisers) but any such third-party reporting shall not include information which may identify an individual customer. | Anonymised/<br><br>aggregated: Account information | Legitimate Interest |
| Manage our networks and understand network usage<br><br>• To protect our networks and manage the volumes of calls, texts, and other uses of our networks. For example, we identify peak periods of use so we can try and ensure the networks can handle the volume at those times; | Traffic data<br><br>Location data | Legitimate Interest |
| Manage our networks and understand network usage<br><br>• To understand how you use our networks, products and services. That way we can seek to review, develop, and improve these, develop more interesting and relevant products and services, as well as personalising our products and services. | Traffic data<br><br>Location data | Consent |
| Improving roaming services<br><br>• To improve your roaming experiences and understand how Vodafone is performing in providing roaming services, whether Roaming Services and related products are working as intended, or whether improvements are needed to make roaming better. Vodafone uses personal data such as your name, email address, mobile phone number and call records in order to do this. Vodafone creates aggregated and statistical management reports from this information that do not identify you individually. Vodafone may also take this personal data and anonymise it so that more in-depth analysis of our roaming services can be undertaken. This helps Vodafone to develop its roaming services for customers without identifying users in an individual way. | Anonymised/<br><br>aggregated:<br><br>Contact details<br><br>Credential information<br><br>Traffic data | Legitimate interest |
| Voice recording of Customer Centre calls<br><br>• For staff training, ensuring quality of engagement and verification of your identity Vodafone record calls made to and from our call centres. | Account information<br><br>Content data | Legitimate Interest. |
| Content of your interactions with us (customer care call recordings, live chat transcripts)<br><br>• We will analyse samples of your interactions with us to improve our services by identifying trends in queries and issues that we receive. This may be done by automated means.<br><br>• We may use the content of your interactions with us to help us create efficiencies and to improve the tools that we use to communicate with you and ensure the quality and accuracy of these services e.g. our automated live chat feature. | Account information<br><br>Content data | Legitimate Interest. |

### Marketing and tailoring our service to you

We process your personal information for marketing and advertising purposes, such as to let you know about new products or services and send you special offers, as well as to help us tailor our service to you.

You can manage your marketing permissions, and your preferences for the data we use to tailor these communications at any time by visiting [Your Privacy Settings](#privacysettings).

| How is your information used? | What data is used? | Lawful basis |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Marketing<br><br>• We process this data for the purpose of sending you marketing communications. We can further tailor these messages using your calling and messaging activities, location information and browsing information, if you have authorised that we process this information for this purpose; | Contact details<br><br>Your preferences<br><br>Browsing history<br><br>Account information<br><br>Location data | Consent |
| Marketing<br><br>•. We will also contact you to let you know about products and services of other Vodafone Group companies and those of other companies which we think may interest you depending on your marketing preferences. | Contact details<br><br>Your preferences<br><br>Browsing history<br><br>Account information<br><br>Location data | Legitimate interest |
| Marketing<br><br>• As our customer, we will keep you informed generally about new products and services, send you newsletters or white papers, invite you to participate in a survey or let you know about offers, promotions, prize draws or competitions. We tailor these messages based on the sorts of products and services you’ve bought from us (for example, we know not to market to you if you’re in the middle of your phone contract). | Contact details<br><br>Account information<br><br>Questionnaire answers | Legitimate interest |
| Personalised/targeted advertising online<br><br>• To deliver advertising that is relevant to you, you’ll also see targeted advertising online based on the use of cookies. This is known as interest-based advertising. It can be on websites belonging to the Vodafone Group, those of other organisations, as well as other online media channels such as social media sites. We may also combine data collected via the cookies with other data we have collected. If you don't want any information processed through the use of cookies, check our [Cookies](#cookies) section. It explains how to control and opt out of cookies.<br><br>• Remember that not providing consent for interest-based advertising won’t stop advertisements from being displayed – but they won’t be tailored to your interests. | Cookie data<br><br>Browsing history<br><br>Account information | Consent |
| Research and analytics<br><br>We use a variety of analytics methods, including what is commonly referred to as “Big data analytics”. Big data analytics are mathematically driven analysis techniques on large and varied data sets (that is why it is “big” data) to uncover hidden patterns and hitherto unrevealed trends. At Vodafone, we take governance of big data analytics seriously. Our data scientists are required to sign up to a Code of Ethics. We have a strict use case process that requires that privacy and data protection law checks are carried out before any use case commences. We have strict rules for anonymisation and disidentified techniques where appropriate.<br><br>We use our analytics to:<br><br>• Perform market research and to carry out research and statistical analysis, including to monitor how customers use our networks, products and services on an anonymous or personal basis;<br><br>• Provide reports to third parties (such reports don’t contain information which may identify you as an individual). These can be to third parties such as content providers and advertisers, or as part of Vodafone Analytics. | Account information | Legitimate interest |
| Research and analytics<br><br>• We will always seek your consent before using “Big data analytics” to process location and traffic data. | Location Data<br><br>Traffic Data | Consent |

### Profiling, Fraud Management and Security

Profiling consists of the use of personal data in an automated form in order to evaluate certain personal aspects relating to an individual. We will process your personal information in this way for credit, fraud, and security purposes.

| How is your information used? | What data is used? | Lawful basis |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Credit checks and ID<br><br>• We may carry out a credit check when you apply for a contract for any products or services with us.<br><br>• We will also use your personal information for identity verification purposes, for access to your account and for general account management. We sometimes supplement the information we collect about you with information from other sources to assess the accuracy of the information that we hold. | Financial details<br><br>Account information<br><br>Credential information | Performance of your contract |
| Fraud Prevention & Security<br><br>• We will process your data and data received from third parties to protect and detect misuse or damage to our networks and to protect against and detect fraud across our products and services<br><br>Fraud management and law enforcement<br><br>• We may be obligated to release information, including information from third parties if it’s reasonable for the purpose of protecting us against fraud, defending our rights or property, or to protect our legitimate interests or the interests of our customers. | Traffic data<br><br>Credential information<br><br>Account information<br><br>Financial details<br><br>Third Party Data<br><br>Information about your device or connectivity<br><br>Cookies | Legitimate interest |
| Network Security<br><br>• We will process your traffic data in order to protect and detect misuse or damage to our networks or to detect and resolve fraudulent use of our networks (and our partner roaming networks) and to solve technical issues you are experiencing. | Anonymous and aggregated contact details or credential related information<br><br>Traffic data | Legitimate interest |
| Physical Security<br><br>• We may use CCTV footage to safeguard our stores and sites. | Images<br><br>Video footage | Legitimate interest |

### To comply with mandatory legal obligation

Under certain circumstances, it is necessary for us to process your personal information in order to comply with the law, for example, when responding to law enforcement requests for data or to comply with tax requirements.

| How is your information used? | What data is used? | Lawful basis | Legislation applicable |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Accounting and tax requirements | Financial details<br><br>Account information | Compliance with mandatory legal obligation | Companies Act 2014 |
| Law enforcement purposes<br><br>• We also may need to release your information to comply with our legal obligation to respond to the authorities’ lawful demands. Your personal data shall only be provided when there is a legal basis to do so in accordance with the law and pursuant to an exhaustive evaluation of all legal requirements. | Account information<br><br>Data about the Device<br><br>Traffic Data<br><br>Location data | Compliance with mandatory legal obligation | Data Protection Act 2018<br><br>Communications (Retention of Data) Act 2011, as amended by the Communications (Retention of Data) (Amendment) Act 2022 |
| Complaint handling purposes<br><br>• Regarding how Vodafone handles your personal data<br><br>Complaint handling purposes<br><br>• Regarding the processing of electronic communications content and of metadata carried out in connection with the provision and use of electronic communications services | Account information<br><br>Customer Relationship  <br>Management data<br><br>Data about the Device and SIM | Compliance with mandatory legal obligation | Data Protection Act 2018<br><br>European Communities (Electronic Communications Networks and Services) (Privacy and Electronic Communications) Regulations 2011 (“the ePrivacy Regulations”) |
| Sharing caller ID and location data with emergency services<br><br>Sharing account data to national registers | Account information<br><br>Data about the Device<br><br>Traffic Data<br><br>Location data<br><br>Account information | Compliance with mandatory legal obligation | European Union (Electronic Communications Code) Regulations 2022 |
| Nuisance Communications purposes<br><br>Implementing a voice firewall to identify and block scam or fraudulent calls, or to flag calls as “Likely Scam”. | Traffic Data | Compliance with mandatory legal obligation | European Union (Electronic Communications Code) Regulations 2022<br><br>24/24 Combatting scam calls and texts (ComReg)<br><br>D13/24 Decision Instrument for Voice Firewall Specification (ComReg) |

### How we share your personal information

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group
    
*   Partners or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used;
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Ireland Limited, or Vodafone Group;
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law;
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement;
    
*   Emergency services (if you make an emergency call), including your approximate location;
    
*   Third parties for joint promotions with that third party;
    
*   Partner organisations we’ve carefully chosen so they can contact you about their products and services (which may or may not include Vodafone products and services). We’ll ask for your consent before sharing this information;
    
*   Other third parties when you are signing up to their service and it is used by them for authentication and fraud-prevention purposes;
    
*   Third parties that we advertise with, such as Facebook, in order to serve you advertisements online;
    
*   Third parties that we use to serve you marketing.

### International Data Transfers

We may need to transfer your information to other Vodafone Group companies (for instance our Vodafone Intelligence Solutions centres located in Egypt, Hungary, Romania, Albania and India, who provide customer support) or service providers in countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

The EEA consists of countries in the European Union, Switzerland, Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway: they are considered to have equivalent laws when it comes to data protection and privacy.

This kind of data transfer will happen if our servers (i.e. where we store data) or our suppliers and service providers are based outside the EEA, or if you use our services and products while visiting countries outside this area.

If Vodafone sends your information to a country that is not in the EEA, we will make sure that your information is properly protected. We will always ensure to conduct a transfer impact assessment and ensure that there is a proper legal agreement that covers the data transfer. In addition, if the country is not considered to have laws that are equivalent to EU data protection standards or deemed adequate by the European Commission (see [list of adequacy decisions](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/adequacy-decisions_en)), then we will implement additional technical security and organisational safeguards such as asking the third party to enter into a legal agreement containing standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission that reflects those standards.

### How long we keep your personal information

We’ll store your information for as long as we must by law. If there’s no legal requirement, we’ll only store it for as long as we need to.

Subject to the above, the following specific retention periods will be followed:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Type of Record or Information | Retention Period |
| Call Traffic Details (records of call and SMS communication, i.e. Time and duration of call, originating number, destination number, quantity of data used, approximate location based on network information, and details of your device.) | Up to 24 months plus current month for billing and our purposes (as described above under "To provide you with your service" and in our general terms and conditions). The call detail element of your standard bill will be severed and deleted after 24 months (plus current month) to facilitate customer queries and debt collection. |
|     | Interconnect call records (i.e. the records of calls made to or received from other networks) are retained for 12 months for inter-operator billing purposes. |
|     | To comply with legal obligations, call traffic records will be retained for a period of 12 months (plus current month). This retention will take place in a restricted access secure system and will not be used for Vodafone's commercial purposes. |
| Invoices & Statements | 6 years plus current year for invoices and statements.<br><br>The call detail element of your standard bill will be severed and deleted after 24 months (plus current month) to facilitate customer queries and debt collection, as described above under "To provide you with your service" . |
| Location Based Information for value added services (excluding network traffic data) | Deleted immediately on completion/ termination of the value-added service. |

We’ll keep some personal information for a reasonable period after your contract with us has finished in case you decide to use our services again; to allow us to answer any questions you might have after you cease your services, or for our own business and reporting requirements. We, or one of our partners, may contact you about Vodafone services during this time if you haven’t opted out of receiving marketing communications from us.

### Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as emails) are not secure unless they have been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.  
We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So, make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.  
The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.

You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including those offered by Google, Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) or using third-party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information.

Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies. You should make sure you’re familiar with these.

### Your rights

Right to correct personal data

You have the right to have information held about you corrected if it is not accurate. If any of the information that we have on file relating to your account needs to be updated, or you think it may be inaccurate, you can log in to My Vodafone to update it ([Login > My account](https://n.vodafone.ie/home/login.html)) or contact our [Customer Services](https://n.vodafone.ie/support.html) team.  

Right to access personal data

You have the right to make a request for a copy of the personal data that Vodafone holds about you. To make this request as an individual or an authorised 3rd party, please fill out the [online form](https://binaries.vodafone.co.uk/tizrehont83j/122j4pENa7QlOO086rERsd/ea767982fdfa0a00b6ce07398a8c95e8/subject-access-request-form.pdf) or post it to the address on the form. Alternatively, you can contact the [Customer Services team](https://n.vodafone.ie/support.html). We will take reasonable steps to confirm your identity before issuing any copy of your personal information.  

Right to data portability

You have the right to be able to take with you data you provided to us in certain circumstances. For example, Vodafone ensures that you can take your data with you by allowing you to download your monthly bills, at the click of a button, in a format of your choice. To do this, log in to [My Vodafone](https://n.vodafone.ie/home/login.html) and go to your billing area. Some specific apps and services allow you to take out the informed stored by the user into Vodafone’s cloud and hosting services, for example Backup+.  

Right to restrict use of your data

If you feel the data we hold on you is inaccurate or believe we shouldn’t be processing your data, please contact our Customer Care team on 1907 to discuss your rights. In certain circumstances, you will have the right to ask us to restrict processing.  

Right to erasure

Vodafone strives to only process and retain your data for as long as we need to. In certain circumstances, you have the right to request that we erase personal data of yours that we hold. If you feel that we are retaining your data longer than we need, it is worth first checking that your contract with Vodafone has been terminated, which you can do by contacting our Customer Care team on 1907. If your contract with Vodafone has been terminated, we may still have lawful grounds to process your personal data (for more information on retention periods, see previous How Long We Keep Your Personal Information For).  

Right to object to processing where we rely on our legitimate interests:

Please contact our Customer Care team on 1907 or email us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).  

Right to withdraw consent

You can withdraw your consent anytime after giving it. Depending on how you provided your consent, you should be able to withdraw your consent in the same way. You can also contact our Customer Care team on 1907 or email us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).  

To opt out of Marketing messages

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, SMS MMS, phone or post).

There are various ways to opt out:

*   Log in to your Privacy Settings to manage your permissions; your [Privacy Settings](#privacysettings) will also provide you with the ability to opt out or into receiving personalised marketing.
    
*   Contact our customer services team – see the [contact us page](https://n.vodafone.ie/support.html);
    
*   Click the link at the end of a marketing email or text to unsubscribe;
    
*   Tell the adviser if you receive a marketing call;
    
*   Disable push notification messages, including marketing messages, at any time in our apps by changing the notification settings on your device or by uninstalling the app;

Email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for guidance.

Opting out does not mean that you won’t any longer receive service-related messages. You will continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise).

To opt out of receiving marketing communications from other Vodafone Group companies, just contact them directly.

In some cases, you may receive marketing from Vodafone, even if you’re not a customer or never had contact with Vodafone. This is a result of third-party marketing lists which Vodafone may acquire from time to time. If you’ve registered to opt out of such marketing, you shouldn’t receive such communications. If you do, we ask that you let us know immediately.  

To manage Cookies and understand more about what they are

Want to disable a cookie, or understand more about what these are? Check the [Cookies](#cookies) section of this notice for full details on how to do this.  

How to lodge a complaint

If you want to contact us about any of your rights or to complain about how we use your information, contact our [Customer Services](https://n.vodafone.ie/support.html) team or email us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We’ll do our best to help, but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact the Data Protection Commission. Contact details for the Data Protection Commissioner are:

*   Email: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
    
*   Phone: +353 (1) 765 01 00 or 1800 437 737
    
*   In writing: Data Protection Commission, 6 Pembroke Row, Dublin 2, D02 X963, Ireland

Privacy and products
--------------------

Get the details of how we utilize your data carefully to deliver personalized products and services like apps, TV and broadband.

tab NaN of 0

Apps

tab NaN of 0

Mobile

tab NaN of 0

Home broadband and phone

tab NaN of 0

TV

tab NaN of 0

Analytics and Marketing

tab NaN of 0

OneNumber

tab NaN of 0

V by Vodafone

### Vodafone products

There are a range of Vodafone apps. This Privacy Statement also applies to those apps, but there will also be an additional Privacy Supplement provided with the app itself with more specific information. In those cases, both will apply.

When you download or use a Vodafone app, information may be accessed from or stored on your device. This will let it operate and function as well as remember you.

To provide you with the service, communicate with you and to work to improve our services, we’ll need to collect information about your device (for example, type, unique identifiers, its operating system, if you’re using 3G or 4G, etc.), app ID and information about your use of the app. Additional information also may be collected to provide you with the requested service.

Each app will set out the preferences it requires to operate, some of which you may be able to opt out of in some cases.

Opting out of certain preferences may, however, affect the functionality of certain services and apps. For example, if you opt out of the location-based feature on your device, you may find that an app doesn’t operate.

It’s important to flag that, where you choose to download or use an app not operated by Vodafone, those apps are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies. Make sure you’re familiar with those before downloading or using that app. We can’t be responsible for the security and content of such third-party apps.

### My Vodafone app

MyVodafone application is a self-service app that helps you stay on top of your plan or prepaid account. You can view and pay bills, recharge your prepaid service, check your usage and update your account settings. To provide you with features of MyVodafone, to send you personalized recommendations as well as to help improve our products and services MyVodafone will share certain information from your device with us.

This privacy supplement defines how your information is used by the MyVodafone application. Please read [Vodafone’s full privacy policy](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy).

What information we collect

When you use the basic features of MyVodafone, for example, check your billing details, view your data plans, view information about how much data a particular app is consuming, or interact with our customer care, information about such interactions is recorded on our servers.

MyVodafone app collects the following information:

App Usage

Information about the performance and use of the MyVodafone app, for example, when and how many times the app has been used, your choices and journeys within the app, app version, last update and application ID.

Information about the quality and use of your connectivity services and apps

Unless you have disabled the collection through the app settings, MyVodafone will regularly send us information about the coverage, connectivity and data usage relating to your connectivity services, information about the applications on your device, your location as well as information about your device, as explained in more detail below.

Coverage, connectivity and data usage

Information about network connectivity and quality for phone calls, internet and data services as experienced by you, as well as statistics about how much your device uses internet services and consumes data, such as:

*   the percentage of time your phone is on the network
    
*   signal strength
    
*   areas of limited or no service
    
*   quality of the mobile overage (2G, 3G, 4G)
    
*   call duration
    
*   how the call ends
    
*   regular tests of whether your device can connect to the internet
    
*   your upload and download speed
    
*   how long it takes to set up a connection to the internet
    
*   WiFi connection quality and MAC addresses of the Wi-Fi hot spots your device can see, and how congested they are
    
*   hourly data use
    
*   how much data your phone uses when its in standby mode
    
*   how much data goes over Wi-Fi connections vs. the mobile network

Applications

Statistics about applications on your devices, such as:

*   which apps are installed on your device
    
*   which apps are started each day and for how long each app is used
    
*   how much data is consumed by each app, how fast each app receives and transmits data and the type and quality of network used for the connection (for example cellular or WiFi and related signal strength)

Device Information

Technical information about your device, such as:

*   phone brand and model
    
*   operating system
    
*   firmware version
    
*   hardware capabilities
    
*   language and locale
    
*   battery state
    
*   memory consumption
    
*   time since last reboot

What we do with this information

We analyse the collected information to diagnose connectivity, coverage or connection quality problems, understand connectivity needs from the usage of mobile data, WiFi and apps, and use such insights to make improvements to our network and services. This may include, for example

*   Improving the quality of network through e.g. better understanding about the exact areas with low network performance or areas of high consumption of data which helps us prioritise new site implementation and otherwise improve the network performance;
    
*   Helping us deal with performance issues caused by poorly performing devices;
    
*   Improving our commercial models and offers based on improved understanding the patterns related to the use of apps and connection quality;
    
*   Improving the performance and design of MyVodafone by understanding which features of the app are popular and how those features perform on different types of devices.

Providing you with personalized assistance and recommendations

We may use the collected information to help us provide more personalized marketing communications to you. We may, for example

*   Recommend a new or a different bundle for you based on the way you use your connectivity services;
    
*   Help you manage your data plans by showing you which apps consume more data;
    
*   Recommend upgrades to your device or promote accessories.

We may combine the collected information with other information we may hold of you.

If you have chosen to provide us with information without being personally identified, all personal identifiers are removed in the app before sending such information to Vodafone and we process the collected information anonymously. We do not intend to use the information to identify you or any other person personally and we have in place appropriate technical and organizational measures to prevent such from happening.

Location data

Unless you have disabled the collection through the app settings, we collect your location data when we measure the items above. For example, we know your rough location from the phone mast and Wi-Fi hot spot your phone is using. When your phone or one of your apps is using GPS location data, we use that to assess location more precisely and sometimes your speed and direction of travel if available with GPS information.

Unless you have chosen otherwise, this information is collected with a personal identifier.

What information we don’t collect

We understand that some of the information we collect may be seen as sensitive. Therefore we have designed the app to reduce the sensitivity of the collected information. For example, we don’t collect information about:

*   any content of your communications, such as sms, email or chat content or your browsing history;
    
*   information about which features of the apps you use or what content you send, receive or otherwise consume through an app.

How long do we keep the information for?

Detailed information about the quality and use of your connectivity services, location and apps is kept no longer than 14 months after it has been collected.

Vodafone may retain aggregated and statistical reports that have been generated using the listed information for a longer period, but as these reports do not identify you as a user, they will not be used in a way that impacts your privacy.

What do we do with the information?

In addition to using the data to the extent necessary to deliver you with the services that you have requested, for example to show you how much data an app consumes, we use the data to help us improve our networks and services as well as to make personalized recommendations to you.

Your choices

Vodafone offers you choices and control over what information you are willing to share from your device. You may choose to:

*   Disable the sending of personal information about the quality and use of your connectivity services, location and apps;
    
*   Disable the sending of any information about the quality and use of your connectivity services, location and apps;
    
*   Disable the sending of information about your use of MyVodafone;
    
*   Disable push-notifications.

NOTE:

if you disable push-notifications, we may still send you marketing SMS or email, or conduct telemarketing if we have your permission to do so. You can get in touch with customer services through the ‘Contact Us’ page on our site to opt out of all marketing communications or to opt out of marketing in one of several ways (such as email, text, phone or post).

Remember that turning off these preferences will impact the level of personalisation we will be able to offer you.

Information security

Vodafone takes technical and organisational security measures as required by law and by industry standards to protect your personal data from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. We take steps to ensure that we only use your personal information as described in this privacy notice and to honour the permission choices that you have made. We only partner with service providers who contract to provide the same level of information security that you can expect from Vodafone.

Who provides the service?

MyVodafone is provided solely by Vodafone Ireland Ltd, registered in Ireland at Mountain View, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, under registered number 326967.

### IOU app

The Vodafone IOU app makes it easy for you to request services that are usually available by SMS command, without having to remember the numbers and commands.

When you make a request through this application, an SMS will be sent from your phone to the appropriate number. When you receive and SMS response you will see the message that was sent.

This privacy supplement defines how your information is used by the IOU Application. Please go to [privacy](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy) to read Vodafone’s full privacy policy.

What information we collect

Information stored in this app is limited to a history of your requests.

What we do with this information

Your request history is not not used for any other purpose, only to let you know how you have used this service.

What information we don’t collect

We don’t collect or use any of your information when you use this app. This app accesses the SMS function on your phone to create a message and send to a Vodafone shortcode number. The content of SMS messages is not collected by the app. Fulfilment of your requested is communicated by SMS.

How long do we keep the information for?

No personal information is collected or stored.

Information security

Vodafone takes technical and organisational security measures as required by law and by industry standards to protect your personal data from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. We take steps to ensure that we only use your personal information as described in this privacy notice and to honour the permission choices that you have made. We only partner with service providers who contract to provide the same level of information security that you can expect from Vodafone.

Who provides the service?

This service is provided by Vodafone Ireland Ltd, registered in Ireland at Mountain View, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, under registered number 326967.

### NetPerform app

This application collects information about the way your phone interacts with our network and services as described below. We hold this data securely and anonymously for 14 months, which lets us view and plan for seasonal variations of network use.

### Network coverage

This application will capture statistics about your connectivity for phone calls. This allows us to diagnose connectivity or connection quality problems and make improvements to our network in your area. We log:

*   the percentage of time your phone is on the network.
    
*   the cell ID and location of the phone masts used and how you move between them, when your phone is active.
    
*   signal strength areas of limited or no service.
    
*   quality of the coverage (2G, 3G, 4G).

### Internet connectivity

This application will capture statistics about your connectivity for internet or data coverage. This allows us to diagnose connectivity or connection quality problems. We log:

*   every hour, a test of whether you can connect to the internet.
    
*   your upload and download speed.  
    
*   the cell ID and location of the phone masts used and how you move between them, when your phone is active.  
    
*   areas of limited or no service.  
    
*   quality of the coverage.  
    
*   how long it takes to set up a connection to the internet.  
    
*   Wi-Fi quality.
    
*   MAC addresses of the Wi-Fi hot spots your device can see

### Call quality and usage

The success or failure of your calling experience can be diagnosed using technical details about the network, your coverage, or your phone’s signal quality during a call. This helps us improve all aspects of your calling experience. We log:

*   the cell ID and location of phone masts serving your incoming and outgoing calls and other masts used if you change location during the call.
    
*   signal strength.
    
*   call duration.
    
*   how the call ends.
    
*   quality of the coverage.

### Data usage

So that we can diagnose the overall usage of the internet data use on different phone models we capture information about how much your device use internet services and consume data. This helps us improve device and network data efficiency for you and other customers based on real world data usage. We log:

*   hourly data use.
    
*   how much data your phone uses when in standby mode.
    
*   how much data goes over Wi-Fi connections vs. the cellular network.

### Applications

So that we can identify trends in data usage that help us allocate capacity for data heavy applications in your area, we assess the data use of the applications on your phone. We log:

*   what apps are installed on your phone.
    
*   how long they are used.
    
*   how much data and how fast each app receives and transmits.

### Location

When we measure the items above related to coverage and usage, we know your rough location from the phone mast Wi-Fi hot spot your phone is using. When your phone or one of your apps is using GPS location data, we use that to assess location more precisely and sometimes speed if available with GPS information. This enables us to identify areas of weak coverage and This information will be used to improve poor performance for you and fellow customers.

### Anonymisation of Information

The network and device improvements that this application is designed for do not require personal information. This means we do not log personal information, all network data is anonymised by the application before it is sent to Vodafone.

*   This app does not log your phone number.
    
*   This app does not log numbers you dial or that dial you.
    
*   This app does not log any content of your communications.
    
*   This app does not log content, sender or receiver information of text messages on your device.
    
*   This app does not log the names of the Wi-Fi hot spots

### One Net app

The One Net application is a self-serve app for desktop, mobile and tablets that helps users connect with their colleagues through instant messaging. Users can manage their availability or online status manually or automatically via Presence. It also provides users the ability to make or receive calls, share files and share desktop.

What information we collect

This app will collect and store your user credentials, email address and phone number for the purpose of creating your user profile.

The features of the One Net App allow you to check your organisation’s phone book, make and receive calls, chat with colleagues, check their availability or online status, move calls between your devices, transfer calls, create conference calls, share your screen and or share files. When you use these features, the app will store the contacts you have uploaded and in order to provide this functionality to you.

What information we don’t collect  

We understand that some of the information we collect may be seen as sensitive. Therefore, we have designed the app to reduce the sensitivity of the collected information. For example, we don’t collect information about:

*   any content of your communications, such as sms, email or chat content, or your browsing history;
    
*   information about which features of the apps you use or what content you send, receive or otherwise consume through an app.

What information we share

In order to provide this service to you, Vodafone use the services of third party suppliers. Where personal data is shared, we will always ensure that the appropriate contractual agreements are in place to protect your data.

Your choices

The One Net app is not essential for use of One Net services. If you choose to use this application, you can disable your online status by enabling the 'Offline' option in the app.

Information security  

Vodafone takes technical and organisational security measures as required by law and by industry standards to protect your personal data from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. We take steps to ensure that we only use your personal information as described in this privacy notice and to honour the permission choices that you have made. We only partner with service providers who contract to provide the same level of information security that you can expect from Vodafone.

Who provides the service?

One Net app is provided by Vodafone Ireland. Our registered office is Mountainview, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, Ireland. We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

### TV Anywhere app

The TV Anywhere app is a companion app providing customers access to their subscribed TV content service for use in home and out of home.

This privacy supplement defines how your information is used by the Vodafone TV platform and Vodafone TV Anywhere Apps. Please go [here](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy) to read Vodafone’s full privacy policy.

### What information we collect

In order to provide the functionality of the app, it is necessary to register on the My Vodafone at home web site. This registration requires a username and password that is associated the customer’s TV account. The app authenticates the user through the username and password set up by the user when registering on the My Vodafone at home web portal.

For the provision of the companion app services and functions, through your mobile devices, we collect the IP address and duration, date and time of start and end of the session of use of the application as well as the data regarding its use of the app.

### What we do with this information

We use the information collected to provide you with the various functionalities of the app including service within and outside the national territory (ie EU Members states), complaints and prevention of fraud. We use this data to manage our content rights for in home use and out of home use of the TV Anywhere apps as per the rights available to us from our content partners

At the time of subscription or renewal of the Vodafone TV service, Vodafone may request the necessary information to determine their Member state of residence (using, for example, the information about the installation location of the TV Box or IP address as a means of verification). The data resulting from the use of the IP address, as a means of verification, shall be collected only in binary format.

All information collected is also used for the purpose of providing technical support and customized improvements. In order to improve the services provided, statistical reports may be used.

We provide usage data to our content partners (the Broadcasters) under our terms and conditions of use and delivery of their services. We do not provide any customer identification or device identification as part of this requirement

### What information we don’t collect

The Vodafone TV Anywhere app only collects data strictly necessary for the execution of the various functionalities. Therefore, Vodafone does not handle TV viewing or use of the various functionalities in an identified way.

No Personal Identifier Information is capture on any devices

What choices/options do you have

Vodafone offers you the option of opting out of receiving (not sending) push notifications settings of your device.

### How long do we keep the information for?

Access data for the App TV is retained for 6 months.

The data collected from your devices, such as the IP address and duration, date and time of commencement and end of the session of use of the APP, data on its use of the app, as well as the type of equipment on which the app has been installed.

Vodafone may retain statistical and aggregated information reports on the information generated by the longer periods of time, but these reports do not identify customers and will be used in a way that has no impact on your privacy.

### How we protect your information

Vodafone has implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures as required by industry standards to protect your personal data against unauthorized access, use and disclosure.

Information we share with other companies

We share unidentified usage data with our contracted content partners (the Broadcasters). Vodafone only enters into partnerships with service providers that guarantee the same level of service information, security and privacy policies you expect from Vodafone.

### Information security

Vodafone takes technical and organizational security measures as required by law and by industry standards to protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. We take steps to ensure that we only use your personal information as described in this privacy notice and to honour the permission choices that you have made. We only partner with service providers who contract to provide the same level of information security that you can expect from Vodafone.

### Who provides the service?

The Vodafone TV Anywhere app is a service provided by Vodafone Ireland Ltd., Central Park, Mountainview, Sandyford, Dublin 24

### Secure Net - from 21 March 2022

Secure Net – Privacy Statement

This privacy supplement gives some additional information specific to Secure Net and the accompanying App.

Secure Net is a security product that provides additional protection when browsing on our mobile or fixed networks with any of your devices capable of connecting to the internet via these networks. It also allows you to manage your child’s access to the internet with a variety of parental controls.

For general information about how we process your data as part of providing mobile connectivity, you can view our main privacy policy [here](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy)

Last updated: 20.09.2021

Who we are

We are Vodafone Ireland Limited and we are a member of the Vodafone Group.

In this privacy statement:

“Vodafone/we/us/our” means Vodafone Ireland Limited;

“third party” means someone who is not you or us; and

“Vodafone Group” means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital.

Our registered office is Mountainview, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, Ireland. We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

How to contact us

Your opinion matters to us. If you have any queries about our Privacy Statement or practices, please contact us.

Our main switchboard is (01) 2037000 or you can email us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

You may contact our Data Protection Officer by email at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or writing to Mountainview, Leopardstown, Dublin 18.

Personal information we collect about you

Information we collect about you

The types of information we process about you and any devices you register with the service when you use Secure Net and the accompanying App are:

*   Your browsing activity on the network; Secure Net is a service that uses a process Domain Name System (DNS) Filtering on websites you are navigating to you in order to protect you from malicious sites and malware. This means for example, that if we know a certain website or app traffic has been blacklisted because it contains harmful content, we’ll warn you that you shouldn’t proceed to that site before you land on it. We do not use this information for other purposes;
    
*   Your phone number, tariff information and price plan;
    
*   Information about devices that are set up to be protected by Secure Net or to be subject to parental controls. For example, we collect information on the type of connected device that you are using (such as whether it’s a mobile device, a laptop, a gaming console or smart home devices, and their manufacturers) and its unique device identifier (for example, the IMEI number, the device’s mobile phone number, or the MAC address of the device’s wireless network interface);
    
*   If you activate the Secure Net cleaning tool, we will access data from your device to help remove security threats from your device;
    
*   The names or nicknames you add when creating family profiles;
    
*   If you are adding children’s profiles, we’ll ask for their age range – this is so we can restrict age-inappropriate content; and
    
*   Your credential information such as passwords, hints and similar security information used for authentication and access to accounts and services. This could be your Vodafone ID credentials if you set up your login via this method.

We’ll also get information about how you use our products and services, such as:

*   Details of your use of our services – for example, we can see whether or not a site has been blocked and keep a limited record of this information for service and customer care (see How long we keep your personal information for), or how often you interact with our online portal or App dashboard to see summaries of your threat protection or parental controls, or the sorts of parental controls you are setting; and
    
*   We also collect anonymous analytics information on how our customers use the Secure Net App or the online portal in order to improve your experience and troubleshoot (for example, we can see whether certain functionalities are not working as intended and fix them or how much our customers use the parental control functionalities).

When we collect your personal information

We collect your personal information when:

*   You browse the internet on a mobile or fixed connection with any of your devices when you have an active Secure Net subscription;
    
*   You activate and use the cleaning tool feature of the App.
    
*   You interact with the App or online Portal (where you can see what threats have been blocked or set any parental controls); and
    
*   When content is blocked as a result of the security protections or when a parental control limits access to certain content.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

1\. Vodafone’s legitimate business interests, for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, and improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the Your Rights section of this policy.

2\. Compliance with a mandatory legal obligation, including for example accounting and tax requirements, which are subject to strict internal policies (such as retention periods), procedures, and your right to restrict usage of your data, which control the scope of legal assistance to be provided; or

3\. Consent you provide where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis. Consent is always presented to you separately and you can withdraw your consent at any time. For example, we need your consent to process the content of your communications in order to detect and block any security threats.

We will require your consent in order to process your traffic and location data for value added services. If you allow people to use your connectivity services we may not be able to identify them (for example guest WIFI users or people using your ‘mobile hotspot’). Therefore, we will rely on the consent of the account holder who will then be responsible for informing users on how their traffic data will be processed when using services supplied to you.

Secure Net is an optional service, which you can deactivate at any time. To do so, you can navigate to the Secure Net portal at https://securenet.vodafone.ie or via the link sent to you in your welcome SMS or alternatively, you can contact our Customer Services team at 1907.

How we use your personal information

To provide you with your service  
In order for us to protect you from security threats and to apply any parental control rules you may have set, we view your browsing activity in order to do so. We do not use this information for marketing or personalised profiling and it is retained for a limited period of time.

Profiling & automated decision making  
Our threat monitoring is based on profiling and automated decisions; for example, websites we block are based on the intelligence we have gathered. You can, at any time, go into your portal or App and view why something has been blocked (for example, if it was malicious or contained malware). You can also customise which websites are limited when parental controls are on outside of the default list provided.

To improve our service  
We collect anonymous, de-identified or aggregate information in order to improve the service we offer to everyone. None of these analytics are linked back to you in any way.

Service messages  
From time to time we’ll send you monthly summaries of the threats that have been blocked. You can turn these off in your account settings if you no longer wish to receive them via the app notification settings or by contacting Vodafone customer services.

How we share your personal information

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group;
    
*   Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used;
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Limited, or Vodafone Group;
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law; or
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.

International data transfers

All data is stored in our data centres in Germany and in whichever local market of whom you are a customer.

How long we keep your personal information for

We’ll store your information for as long as we have to by law. If there’s no legal requirement, we’ll only store it for as long as we need to.

Browsing history

We keep a limited record of your browsing history for service and customer care purposes only for 30 days. Vodafone does not repurpose your browsing for the purposes of marketing or personalised profiling.

*   For example, if you believe that we should not have blocked a site, we can check that for you; or
    
*   In order for you to be able to view a history of the protection provided (such as number of security threats blocked by the service) with the App or the Secure Net portal.

Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as emails) aren’t secure unless they’ve been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.

The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.

Your rights

Here's how you can exercise your rights. If you have any questions, please contact our Customer Service.

Right to correct personal data  
You have the right to have information held about you corrected if it is not accurate. If what we hold on you needs updating, or you think it may be inaccurate, you can log in to [My Vodafone](https://n.vodafone.ie/home/login.html) to update it (Login > My account) or contact our [Customer Care](https://n.vodafone.ie/support.html).

Right to access personal data  
You have the right to make a request for a copy of the personal data that Vodafone holds about you. To make this request as an individual or an authorised 3rd party, please [download this form](https://binaries.vodafone.co.uk/tizrehont83j/122j4pENa7QlOO086rERsd/ea767982fdfa0a00b6ce07398a8c95e8/subject-access-request-form.pdf) and email or post it to the address on the form. Alternatively, you can contact the Customer Care on 1907.

Right to data portability  
You have the right to be able to take with your data you provided to us in certain circumstances. For example, Vodafone ensures that you can take your data with you by allowing you to download your monthly bills, at the click of a button, in a format of your choice. In order to do this, log in to My Vodafone and go to your billing area. Some specific apps and services allow you to take out the information stored by the user into Vodafone’s cloud and hosting services, for example Backup+. For any queries send an email to [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Right to object to use of personal data

In some cases you will have the right to object to use of personal data. Contact our Customer Care team on 1907 or email us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

How to lodge a complaint  
If you want to contact us about any of your rights or if complain about how we use your information, contact our Customer Care team at 1907 or email us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We’ll do our best to help but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact the Data Protection Commission who may be contacted by email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or by post to Data Protection Commission, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, or 32 AP23 Co Laois.

Right to restrict use of your data  
If you feel data we hold on you is inaccurate or believe we shouldn’t be processing your data, please contact our Customer Care team on 1907 to discuss your rights. In certain circumstances you will have the right to ask us to restrict processing.

Right to erasure  
Vodafone strives to only process and retain your data for as long as we need to. In certain circumstances you have the right to request that we erase personal data of yours that we hold. If you feel that we are retaining your data longer than we need, it is worth first checking that your contract with Vodafone has been terminated which you can do with our Customer Care team on 1907. If your contract with Vodafone has been terminated, we may still have lawful grounds to process your personal data (for more information on retention periods see How Long We Keep Your Personal Information For).

If you believe that Vodafone is processing personal data that is not required, or no longer required for our business purposes, please complete the online form [here](https://n.vodafone.ie/forms/consumer/data-deletion-request.html) to submit an erasure request.

Our cookie policy

Cookies are tiny text files that are stored on your computer, tablet or mobile phone when you visit a website. The cookies mean that the website will remember you and how you've used the site every time you come back.

Cookies themselves don't hold personal information such as your name or bank details. And in many cases, we won’t be able to link the information we collect by using a cookie back to you. They can, however, help us to find information once you're logged in or help us link your browsing information to you and your personal information, for example, when you choose to register for a service, white paper or newsletter.

First party cookies

First party cookies originate from the same domain as the website you’re currently visiting.

|     |     |     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Name | Essential / Non-essential | First Party / Third Party | Lifetime/ Max-Age | Domain | Description |
| x-vf-sn-cross-token | Non-essential | First Party | 1 minute | [.vodafone.ie](http://securenet.vodafone.pt/) | Used for authentication between the Convergent Portal and the Classic Web Portal. |
| VF-UUID | Non-essential | First Party | 10 years | [.securenet.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) | Used by Vodafone to collect analytics data. |
| VF-SID | Non-essential | First Party | 36 minutes | [.securenet.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) |     |
| VF-OPT | Non-essential | First Party | Session | [.securenet.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) |     |
| VF-BINS | Non-essential | First Party | Session | [.securenet.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) |     |
| \_ga | Non-essential | First Party | 2 years | [.securenet.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) | The most common cookies used by Google Analytics/Firebase to track user sessions. Other cookies related to analytics and managed by the Firebase Javascript dependency might be used and changed over time. |
| \_ga\_<firebase\_ | Non-essential | First Party | 2 years | [.securenet.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) |     |
| measurement\_id> |     |     |     |     |     |
| \_gid | Non-essential | First Party | 1 day | [.securenet.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) |     |
| incap\_ses\_770\_2431481 | Essential | First Party | Session | [.securenet.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) | WAF (Incapsula) |
| Mandatory session cookie |     |     |     |     |     |
| nlbi\_\* | Essential | First Party | Session | [.securenet.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) | WAF (Incapsula) |
| It is a load balancer Cookie to ensure requests by a client are sent to the same origin server. |     |     |     |     |     |
| visid\_incap\_2345399 | Essential | First Party | 1 year | [.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) | WAF (Incapsula) |
| The cookie on which we relate sessions to a specific visitor (visitor representing a specific browser on a specific computer) |     |     |     |     |     |
| vsisd\_incap\_24314781 | Essential | First Party | 1 year | [.securenet.vodafone.ie](https://securenet.vodafone.ie/) | WAF (Incapsula) |
|     |     |     |     |     | The cookie on which we relate sessions to a specific visitor (visitor representing a specific browser on a specific computer) |

Controlling your cookies

You can control how you use cookies in your browser. If you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by any website - including a Vodafone website, you should do this through the web browser settings for each web browser you use, on each device you use to access the internet.

Information on controlling and deleting cookies, including on a wide variety of browsers, is also available at [allaboutcookies.org](https://allaboutcookies.org/)

### Secure Net - before 21 March 2022

Vodafone Secure Net is a service that offers protection against security threats including viruses, trojans, spyware, adware and unwanted programs.

This supplement defines how your information is used by by Secure Net. Please go to privacy section to read Vodafone’s full privacy policy.

What information we collect

Please also refer to the full Vodafone Ireland privacy policy on [this page.](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy)

Vodafone will collect and use your data, including usage statistics, to:

*   Improve the service;
    
*   Improve the security of the Vodafone Network; and
    
*   Provide you with a higher level of security and protection whilst you are on the Vodafone Network.

For how long do you keep my personal data?

Vodafone may retain aggregated and statistical reports that have been generated using your personal data and anonymised data for a longer period, but as these reports cannot identify you as a user, they cannot be used in a way that impacts your privacy.

Information security

Vodafone takes technical and organizational security measures as required by law and by industry standards to protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. We take steps to ensure that we only use your personal information as described in this privacy notice and to honour the permission choices that you have made. We only partner with service providers who contract to provide the same level of information security that you can expect from Vodafone.

Who provides the service?

Vodafone Secure Net are provided solely by Vodafone Ireland Limited, registered in Ireland at Mountainview, Leopardstown, Dublin 18 under registered number 326967.

### Secure Net - before 15th April 2020

Vodafone Secure Net is a service that offers protection against security threats including viruses, trojans, spyware, adware and unwanted programs. Vodafone SecureNet Find & Ring operates as a complimentary service that helps locate your device. It requires access to your device’s location data.

This supplement defines how your information is used by by Secure Net and the complimentary Find & Ring feature. Please go to privacy section to read Vodafone’s full privacy policy.

What information we collect

In addition to your device location data, we will also ask you to enter your email address when first setting it up. This is for product registration so that we can activate Find and Ring.

Please also refer to the full Vodafone Ireland privacy policy on [this page.](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy)

This is the email address we will use for account recovery. Make sure you keep your account details secure - this is essential for your privacy and security.

Vodafone will collect and use your data, including usage statistics, to:  

*   Improve the service;
    
*   Improve the security of the Vodafone Network; and
    
*   Provide you with a higher level of security and protection whilst you are on the Vodafone Network.

Location information - Secure Net Find & Ring only  

Secure Net Find & Ring will only share location data with your separate permission if you choose to use the app. Secure Net Find & Ring locates your device by making use of the location data assessing the GPS location data, Wifi location data and the network location data that your device uses. This data is broadcast to Vodafone every 3 hours and when the battery is low on your device.

Vodafone only uses the location data from Secure Net Find and Ring to locate your device on your request. We do not sell it or rent it out to third parties.

For how long do you keep my personal data? - (Secure Net Find & Ring only)

Vodafone will retain your email address for as long as you continue to use Secure Net Find & Ring. Vodafone will retain the location data from your device for a maximum of 24 hours. After that time the data will be deleted and no location history is maintained.

Vodafone may retain aggregated and statistical reports that have been generated using your personal data and anonymised data for a longer period, but as these reports cannot identify you as a user, they cannot be used in a way that impacts your privacy.

Information security

Vodafone takes technical and organisational security measures as required by law and by industry standards to protect your personal data from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. We take steps to ensure that we only use your personal information as described in this privacy notice and to honour the permission choices that you have made. We only partner with service providers who contract to provide the same level of information security that you can expect from Vodafone.

Who provides the service?

Vodafone Secure Net and Secure Net Find and Ring are provided solely by Vodafone Ireland Limited, registered in Ireland at Mountainview, Leopardstown, Dublin 18 under registered number 326967.

### Tozi app

[Tozi App Privacy Statement \[PDF, 326.13 KB\]](https://binaries.vodafone.co.uk/tizrehont83j/7xOaFetL0jhcmopxWQMsML/729693b838ffd232979cdffb08d11a41/Tozi_-_Privacy_Notice_from_March_20_2026.pdf)  
[Tozi Child Friendly Privacy Statement \[PDF, 329.60 KB\]](https://binaries.vodafone.co.uk/tizrehont83j/1vLpQ0wOEq9YjT14SqhxGx/a5f0a3d342142c09c7bc4e7fbb4e820a/Tozi_-_child_friendly_privacy_statement_from_March_20_2026.pdf)

### Vodafone Broadband and Gigabox Apps

The Vodafone Broadband and Gigabox Apps allows Ultra Hub 7 and Gigabox modem users to control their Wi-Fi network. You can easily change your Wi-Fi network name and passwords, set up a guest Wi-Fi network, create a schedule for when Wi-Fi is available, and manage the devices connected to your network.

This privacy supplement gives some additional information specific to the Vodafone Broadband and Gigabox Apps (‘App’). For general information about how we process your data as part of the services we provide to you, you can view our main privacy policy here.

###   
Personal information we collect about you

Information we collect about you  
When you use the App and its features, for example check your broadband usage, view your data plans or interact with our customer care, information about such interactions is recorded on our servers. We also collect information about the quality and use of your connectivity services and apps. Personal data we collect includes;

*   Router MAC address
    
*   Router serial number
    
*   MAC address of the devices connected to the router
    
*   Unique line identifier
    
*   User ID
    
*   Subscription ID
    
*   Device ID (Fingerprinting)
    
*   If you choose to name devices with personal names, we will store this data also.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

1.  Vodafone’s legitimate business interests, for example, the analysis of app performance to enhance the product. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the Your Choices section of this policy;
    
2.  In order to meet our contractual obligations where we have committed contractually to provide you with app services or;
    
3.  Consent you provide where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis, for example the personalised data collection (if you have chosen to share this with us) for personalised services and offers. Consent is always presented to you separately and you can withdraw your consent at any time.

### Your Choices

App Settings

The Gigabox app is one of the ways we put you in control as to how to manage your data sharing preferences. In your settings, you can choose:

*   Disable the sending of information about your use of the Gigabox app; or
    
*   Disable push-notifications

Please note: If you disable push-notifications, we may still send you marketing via SMS or email, or conduct telemarketing if we have your permission to do so. You can get in touch with us to opt out of marketing communications (such as email, SMS, phone or post).

### How we use your personal information

To assist our customer care services

*   We can advise you if you are having device performance or connectivity issues.

To improve our networks and services  
We analyse the collected information to diagnose connectivity, coverage or connection quality problems, understand connectivity needs from the usage of mobile data, Wi-Fi and apps, and use such insights to make improvements to our network and services. This may include, for example;

*   Helping us deal with performance issues caused by poorly performing devices;
    
*   Improving our commercial models and offers based on improved understanding the patterns related to the use of apps and connection quality;
    
*   Improving the performance and design of the Gigabox app by understanding which features of the app are popular and how those features perform on different types of devices.

All personal identifiers are removed in the app before sending such information to Vodafone and we process the collected information anonymously. We do not intend to use the information to identify you or any other person personally and we have in place appropriate technical and organisational measures to prevent such from happening.

If you disable the sending of information about your use of the Gigabox App, we still collect a reduced set of anonymous information every time the app is used (goes in foreground/background):

*   app version;
    
*   app last update;
    
*   application ID;
    
*   device make and model;
    
*   date and time the app went in foreground;
    
*   date and time the app went in background;
    
*   router model;
    
*   router firmware version;
    
*   Anonymized Line Id;
    
*   Anonymized Router Serial Number
    
*   Usage information collection (on/off)
    
*   App crashes information

Marketing and profiling  
If we have your permission, we will use the collected information combined with other information we hold about you to help us provide more personalised marketing communications to you. We can, for example  
• Recommend a new or a different bundle for you based on the way you use your connectivity services;  
• Help you manage your data plans by showing you which apps consume more data; and  
• Recommend upgrades to your device or promote accessories.

###   
How we share your personal information

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group;
    
*   Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used;
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Limited, or Vodafone Group;
    
*   Third parties for personalised marketing purposes, where you have given us your permission to do so;
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law; or
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.

### International data transfers

Occasionally we may need to transfer your data outside of the EEA, for example if we have a service provide that we have contracted on our behalf. When Vodafone sends your information to a country that is not in the EEA, we make sure that your information is properly protected. We will always ensure that there is a proper legal agreement that covers the data transfer. In addition, if the country is not considered to have laws that are equivalent to EU data protection standards then we will ask the third party to enter into a legal agreement that reflects those standards.

How long we keep your personal information for

Detailed information about the quality and use of your connectivity services and location is kept no longer than 13 months after it has been collected.

Vodafone may retain aggregated and statistical reports that have been generated using the listed information for a longer period, but as these reports do not identify you as a user, they will not be used in a way that impacts your privacy.

### Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

### Mobile

Every time you use your mobile phone, a record is kept. This includes the number you called or sent a text or picture message to, the length, date and time of a call, text or picture message and your approximate location at the time that the communication takes place (based on the location of the nearest cell that you sent that call or message from). The same is also recorded every time you receive an incoming call or message. We don’t, however, keep a record of the content of your calls or messages.

We’ll also keep a record of the data you use. This will record things like how much you spend in or out of bundle, or in an app, to enable us to charge you the right amount on your next bill as well as other things such as alerting you if you are close to your usage limit, fix faults and send you service messages. We don’t keep a record of the content of any messages you send using your data.

As part of providing the service, we need to understand and manage traffic flows on the network. So this also means we require information about your data usage. This includes capturing IP addresses and traffic data such as the websites you’ve visited. We’ll also have information about the Vodafone apps you use including location data. Having this information also means that we’re able to provide you with services that you request and work to improve them.

Capturing the websites you’ve visited doesn’t mean that we will have a history of your web-browsing as this is limited for a short real time period to enable the connection to be made. Details about websites visited may be stored for analytical purposes, such as counting the amount of times a specific web URL is visited, but this is only captured in a generic format and cannot be linked back to individual customers. For more information on your browsing history, see our [Cookies Policy](#cookies).

To help us provide you with services and work to improve them, we need to understand how you use your mobile. This means that we’ll have certain information about your device such as its make and model, the device ID, which operating system it uses, and if you’re using 3G or 4G.

It’s important to flag to you that third-party content providers like Spotify, and Sky Sports will have their own terms of use, and privacy and cookies policies that apply to you when you access their content on your mobile. Make sure you’re familiar with these and understand how they use your information before downloading or using their services.

### Phone

When you use your phone a record is kept of the call traffic details , which is the time and date of the call, the number called and the duration of the call. We do not record the content of the call.

### Home broadband

As part of providing this service, we need to understand and manage traffic flows on the network.

To do this, we need information about your broadband usage. This includes capturing IP addresses, device ID (fingerprinting), and traffic data such as the websites you’ve visited. We’ll also have information about the Vodafone apps that you use. Having this information means we’re able to provide you with services that you request and work to improve them.

Capturing the websites you’ve visited doesn’t mean that we will have a history of your web-browsing as this is limited for a short real time period to enable the connection to be made. Details about websites visited may be stored for analytical purposes, such as counting the amount of times a specific web URL is visited, but this is only captured in a generic format and cannot be linked back to individual customers. For more information on your browsing history, see the [cookies policy](#cookies).

For more information on using apps, see the app section above.

It’s important to flag that third-party content providers such as Spotify and Sky Sports will have their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies that apply when you access their content using broadband. Make sure you’re informed on these and understand how your information is used before downloading or using their services.

### Gigabit Smart Services

### Who's Home

The Vodafone Broadband smart service: “Who’s Home” is a limited access service available for eligible customers using a compatible Vodafone router (the “Ultra Hub 7” modem) and the Vodafone Broadband App (“App”).

Users of the “Who’s Home” feature will be notified (in the App) when registered household members connect or disconnect (their primary mobile device) to the home Wi-Fi connection. A connection to Wi-Fi is interpreted as the associated household member arriving home, and a disconnection to Wi-Fi is interpreted as the associated household member leaving the home.

This allows customers to choose to be notified when family members, for example school-going children, arrive or leave home. The service is accessible via the Vodafone Broadband home screen panel of the same name. Users accessing this feature for the first time, will be guided through the setup process. Once the setup is complete, the Who’s Home tile will show all registered members and whether their devices are home or not.

The Supplement defines how your information is used by Vodafone “Who’s Home”.

### Personal information we collect about you

Information we collect

Just like the data collected to provide Vodafone Home Broadband, this service will process data about your devices, such as MAC address and OS version.

We will process names and phone numbers provided by the account holder, when they enter this information to register household members and get notifications about household members leaving or arriving home, based on their primary mobile device disconnecting from or connecting to the Wi-Fi, respectively.

To help us determine how well the service is working, identifiers such as the number of devices set up for the Service, when the service was activated or deactivated is also collected.

How we use the information collected

Vodafone will use your device information, name and number (as provided by the account holder):

To provide the Vodafone Who’s Home service.

To let the account holder know that any registered household members have entered or left the home, determined solely by their mobile phones disconnecting and connecting to home Wi-Fi.

Conduct analytics to determine the success of the product.

What information we don’t collect

Vodafone Who’s Home will not track your device’s movement around the house, for example, we do not collect GPS data.

We don’t collect personal data other than the type of device, unless the account holder provides it (for example, provides your name and phone number) and you have not opted out.

What choices do you have

You may choose to opt out of being included as a household member, i.e. your name and phone number used by the account holder, so that they will be alerted when you enter or leave the home. This can be done by responding to the text message (SMS) sent by the service in the format mentioned.

How long we keep your data

By way of an example, here are some of the data and usage statistics we will collect and how long we will retain it for.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Q&A | What data is involved | How long is it retained for? |
| Service Configuration Information | Devices setup | As long as the service is active |
| Identifiers | Devices configured, service activation and deactivation dates | As long as the service is active |
| App Usage Data | App Usage | 90 days |
| Urban Airship Data | App notifications, usage analytics and campaigns | As long as the service is active |

Vodafone may retain aggregated and statistical reports that have been generated using the listed information for a longer period, but as these reports do not identify you as a user, they will not be used in a way that impacts your privacy.

How we share information

As described in the [Vodafone Ireland Privacy Notice](https://www.vodafone.ie/privacy), we may share information about you with companies in the Vodafone Group and partners or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used. In this case, your data may be stored in environments hosted by cloud service providers and will be access by companies in the Vodafone Group for support, IT, and other internal operations.

### International Transfer

Data will be stored in Germany, but may be accessed from outside the EEA by Vodafone’s support teams. Please see the [Vodafone Ireland Privacy Notice](https://www.vodafone.ie/privacy) for more information on how we transfer data to other Vodafone Group companies.

How we protect your data

Vodafone takes technical and organisational security measures as required by law and by industry standards to protect your personal data from unauthorised access, use or disclosure.

We take steps to ensure that we only use your personal information as described in this privacy notice and to honour the permission choices that you have made.

We only partner with service providers who contract to provide the same level of information security that you can expect from Vodafone.

### Who provides the service?

Vodafone’s Who’s Home service is provided solely by Vodafone Ireland Limited. Registered Office: Mountain View, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, The Connection, Newbury, Berkshire RG14 2FN. Registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

Contact details

If you have any queries in any aspect of this privacy supplement, please contact [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

### Vodafone TV

If you watch TV through the Vodafone TV app, please also read the Apps section on this page.

It’s important to flag that certain content providers may have their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies that may apply to you when you access their content. Content providers include, for example, Netflix, iPlayer. You should check these on their websites to be sure you’re informed on and understand how your information is used.

Vodafone wants you to receive the most benefit from your TV service with us.

In order to be able to provide you with our TV service, and to continually improve it, we need to collect information about how you watch TV. We can do this using the Vodafone TV Box or the Vodafone TV app on your devices. For example, we’ll collect information about what you watch (which may include adverts), how long you watched it for and what you did such as pausing, recording, fast-forwarding, etc.

We’ll collect information about what you used to watch it (such as which Vodafone TV Box or which device) and where you watched it (location data, time zones, etc.). We’ll know what you downloaded or purchased. We’ll also know, for example, the IP addresses for any devices, device IDs and/or unique identifiers, your user IDs and passwords, any device parental control or purchase PIN codes. Your devices such as your Vodafone TV Box will tell us about your use of the services and third-party content, products and services.

We also use the information we collect to be able to charge you the right amount on your next bill (for example, where you have rented a film or have elected to charge Netflix to your Vodafone bill) as well as other things such as fix faults and send you service messages.

We’ll use the information to be able to provide you with localised content, to send you viewing recommendations and analyse what you watched so that we can enhance our services further.

We’ll also use the information to provide reports to third parties such as content providers and advertisers. These reports won’t contain information that may identify you.  

### General

We may use the information you provide us to contact you about offers and promotions including competitions, prize draws and surveys based on how you use our products and services.

We may also contact you to let you know about products and services of Vodafone, Vodafone Group companies and those of other companies which we think may interest you.

We may tailor or personalise the marketing message and its content based on the information you’ve provided to us and your use of Vodafone’s website, products and services.

We’ll assume that you’re comfortable to receive these messages unless you tell us otherwise. We’ll contact you by post, online, phone or push notifications through our apps.

For more information on online advertising, see the Advertising Online section below.

### Analytics

We use a variety of analytics methods, which involve mathematically driven analysis techniques where large and varied data sets uncover hidden patterns and previously unrevealed trends. At Vodafone we take governance of analytics seriously. Our data scientists are required to sign up to a Code of Ethics. We have a strict use case process that requires that privacy and data protection law checks are carried out before any use case commences. We have strict rules ensuring that personal information is anonymised at the appropriate stage in the process so that it is no longer possible to identify an individual.

### How to opt out

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, text, phone or post).

There are various ways to opt out:

*   Contact our customer services team – see the [contact us](https://n.vodafone.ie/support.html) page;
    
*   Click the link at the end of a marketing email or text to unsubscribe;
    
*   Disable push notification messages, including marketing messages, at any time in our apps by changing the notification settings on your device or by uninstalling the app;
    
*   Email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
    
    for guidance.

Opting out does not mean that you won’t receive service-related messages anymore. You will still continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise).

To opt out of receiving marketing communications from other Vodafone Group companies, just contact them directly.

In some cases, you may receive marketing from Vodafone, even if you’re not a customer or never had contact with Vodafone. This is a result of third-party marketing lists which Vodafone may acquire from time to time. If you’ve registered to opt out of such marketing, you shouldn’t receive such communications. If you do, we ask that you let us know immediately by contacting us on 1800200234 or (01)2527218.

### Advertising online

To deliver advertising that is relevant to you, you’ll also see targeted advertising online based on the use of cookies. This is known as interest-based advertising. We may also combine data collected via the cookies with other data we have collected.

You’ll also receive direct marketing based on use of cookies. If you don't want any information processed through the use of cookies, check our [cookies policy](#cookies). It explains how to control and opt out of cookies.

Remember that opting out of interest-based advertising won’t stop advertisements from being displayed – but they won’t be tailored to your interests.

### OneNumber – Privacy Statement

This privacy supplement gives some additional information specific to the OneNumber service and explains how Vodafone process your data to provide you with such service.

For general information about how we process your data as part of providing mobile connectivity, you can view our main privacy policy on [this page](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy).

What is OneNumber?

OneNumber Connectivity Plans provide the ability to share Vodafone airtime and data allowances across multiple devices, you can stay connected to Vodafone’s network on other connected eligible devices, including smartwatches, tablets or Alexa device without WiFi or your phone nearby. To be eligible for OneNumber, you must have a pay monthly plan with us.

Last updated: 26th June 2023

Who we are

We are Vodafone Ireland. We are a member of the Vodafone Group. In this privacy policy:

*   “we/us” means Vodafone Ireland;
    
*   “third party” means someone who is not you or us; and
    
*   “Vodafone Group” means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital.

Our registered office is Mountainview, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, Ireland. We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

Our lead supervisory authority is the Data Protection Commissioner.

*   Email: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
    
*   Phone: [+353 (0)57 868 4757](tel:00353578684757) or [+353 (0)761 104 800](tel:00353761104800)
    
*   In writing: Data Protection Office, 21 Fitzwilliam Square, Dublin 2, D02 RD28.
    
*   How to contact us Your opinion matters to us – if you have any queries about our Privacy Statement or practices, please contact us. Our main switchboard is [(01) 2037000](tel:0035312037000). You may contact our Data Protection Officer by email at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or writing to: Data Protection Officer Vodafone Ireland Mountain View Leopardstown Dublin 18 Ireland

### Personal information we collect about you

Information we collect about you:

*   Your contact details, such as your phone number,  
    
*   Cookies: functional, performance and strictly necessary cookies, please see more details in the Cookies Policy section.
    
*   Data about the Device and SIM: IMSI (International Mobile Subscriber Identity), MSISDN from the device (phone number), make and model from the device.

When we collect your personal information:  
  
We collect your personal information when:

*   We collect your mobile phone number that you use to authenticate yourself. We don’t collect names, addresses or email addresses from your device but we do need access to certain browser attributes (see our Cookie Policy).
    
*   We collect some information about your device and your use of Vodafone OneNumber (for example, language, equipment and usage statistics).
    
*   We’ll share some information with your Vodafone carriers and partners, and get some information back from them: your mobile number and other information about your tariff and the eligible services available to you.

We’ll also get information about how you use our products and services, such as:

*   Details of your use of our services – for example, we can see whether our customers are actively using the service.
    
*   We also collect aggregated analytics information on how our customers use OneNumber in order to improve your experience and troubleshoot.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

1.  Vodafone’s legitimate business interests, for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, and improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the Your Rights section of this policy.
    
2.  Consent you provide where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis. Consent is always presented to you separately and you can withdraw your consent at any time. For example, we need your consent to process your data for marketing purposes.  
    
3.  Performance of your contract or to enter into the contract and to take action on your requests. For example, we process your account information and payment details for monthly billing of the service associated with the airtime plan.

### How we use your personal information

To provide you with your service  
In order for us to provide you with the OneNumber service we are required to process your data to manage such subscription and additional service to the primary airtime plan.

To improve our service  
We collect anonymous, de-identified or aggregate information in order to improve the service we offer to everyone. None of these analytics are linked back to you in any way.

Marketing & profiling

If you are eligible for the OneNumber service with an eligible plan, but are yet to complete the user journey, based on your marketing consent, we may contact you to provide value added service for OneNumber.  
To opt out of Marketing messages or profiling:  
If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, messaging, phone or post).  

To opt out of Marketing messages or profiling: If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, messaging, phone or post).

There are various ways to opt out:

*   If you are a Vodafone consumer mobile customer, you can log in to your My Vodafone account, access ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App, or call [1800 200 234](tel:1800200234) to manage your marketing permissions and to opt out or into receiving personalised marketing.
    
*   All our marketing messages come with an “unsubscribe” link which you can click to unsubscribe;
    
*   Tell the adviser if you receive an outbound marketing call;
    
*   Email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for guidance.

Opting out does not mean that you won’t any longer receive service-related messages, such as messages telling you about your order status or when our Terms & Conditions change. You will still continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise).

### How we share your personal information

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group;
    
*   Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used;
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Limited, or Vodafone Group;  
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law; or
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.

### International data transfers

All data is stored in our data centres in Europe and in whichever local market of whom you are a customer.

### How long we keep your personal information for

Personal data will be stored on the OneNumber platform for 60 days to facilitate subscription and managing of additional services on a primary mobile contract after which we will store and process your information for as long as we have to by law or as long as we need to be able to deliver you the services you have requested.

We’ll keep some personal information for a reasonable period after your contract with us has finished in case you decide to use our services again.

We, or one of our partners, may contact you about Vodafone services during this time if you haven’t opted out of receiving marketing communications from us. Once these periods have expired, we’ll delete that information.

### Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as emails) aren’t secure unless they’ve been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.

The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.

### Your rights

Here's how you can exercise your rights. If you have any questions, please contact our Customer Service.

Right to correct personal data  
You have the right to have information held about you corrected if it is not accurate. If what we hold on you needs updating, or you think it may be inaccurate, you can log in to My Vodafone to update it (Login > My account) or contact our Customer Services team on 1907.

Right to access personal data  
Want a copy of the personal information we hold on you? You can do this by contacting Customer Care on 1907 or through chat on [our website](https://www.vodafone.ie/). We will take all reasonable steps to confirm your identity before issuing any copy of your personal information.

Right to data portability  
You have a right to receive a copy of all personal information that you consented to provide to us, or have provided to us as part of your contract with us. Please contact our Customer Services team on 1907.

Right to object to use of personal data  
In some cases, you will have the right to object to use of personal data. If you do not want your personal information to be used for any purpose, other than those necessary to provide a service to you, please let us know by selecting your data preferences. You can change your preferences at any time using your My Vodafone account. By selecting ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App or by calling [1800 200 234](tel:1800%20200%20234).

Right to erasure  
You have a right to request the erasure of your personal information which we hold about you where the personal information is no longer necessary, where you have withdrawn your consent or where you feel that there is no lawful reason for us to process your personal information.  
  
We will send you confirmation when your request has been completed. Please note that if you have an active service with us, much of the information that we keep about you cannot be deleted as this is required to provide you with the service to you and to provide support to you.  

Right to restrict use of your data  
If you wish to restrict the use of your data by Vodafone, please contact our Customer Services team on 1907. It is helpful to let us know the reason for your restriction request.

How to lodge a complaint  
If you want to contact us about any of your rights, or to enquire or make a complaint about how we use your information, contact our Customer Services team via vodafone.ie or by email at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We’ll do our best to help but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact Data Protection Commission. Contact details for the Data Protection Commissioner are:

*   Email: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
    
*   Phone: [+353 (0)57 868 4757](tel:00353578684757) or [+353 (0)761 104 800](tel:353761104800)
    
*   In writing: Data Protection Office, 21 Fitzwilliam Square, Dublin 2, D02 RD28.

### Our cookie policy

Our cookie and tracking technologies policy

This section is about what cookies and other tracking technologies are, how we use them and how you can manage them.

What are cookies?  
Cookies are small files that are stored on your device when you visit a website. The cookies mean that the website will remember you and how you've used the site every time you come back.  
If you want to know more about cookies, head to aboutcookies.org or allaboutcookies.org (please note: these links open a new window or browser tab).

What are other similar tracking technologies?  
This refers to any other method used to store information, gain access to information, or track activities on your device, such as Local Shared Objects (“flash cookies”), scripts, tracking pixels and plugins, app trackers (including SDKs) on smartphones, tablets, smart TVs or other devices.

How we use cookies/tracking technologies  
We use cookies and other similar tracking technologies to do a number of things. For example, remembering your preferences, recording what you've put in your shopping basket, or counting the number of people looking at a website. We also use them to keep track of what you've bought from us, what you've done on the site, and to make online advertising more relevant to you.

Cookies usually comprise of unique alphanumeric identifier that sits on your browser. In some cases, we won’t be able to link the information we collect by using a cookie back to you. They can, however, enable us to link that information back to you and your personal information, for example, when you log in, or choose to register for a service, or newsletter. We may also use cookies in order to provide you with personalised adverts based on your browsing behaviour.  
We've put our cookies into the following categories, to make it easier for you to understand why we need them:

1.  Strictly necessary – these are used to help make our website work efficiently
    
2.  Performance – these are used to analyse the way our website works and how we can improve it
    
3.  Functionality – these help to enhance your experience by doing things like remembering products you've added to your basket.
    
4.  Targeting/advertising – these are used to share some information with third parties who we advertise with, so we know how you've reached our website. We can also use cookies to identify the parts of the website you’re interested in. We then use this information to show you adverts and pages we think may also be of interest to you, to tailor how we communicate with you, or to tailor the contents of the communications we send to you. If you prefer, you can opt out of these. Tailoring of content means it includes information reflecting the interest you’ve shown in the content of our web pages, or offers or promotions that we think may interest you, and to improve how we respond to your needs.

In addition to the cookies we use on our websites, we also use cookies and similar technologies in some emails and push notifications we send to mobile devices from our apps. These help us to understand whether you have opened the email and how you have interacted with it. If you have enabled images, cookies may be set on your computer or mobile device. Cookies will also be set if you click on any link within the email.

We sometimes use persistent cookies as well as 'session-based' cookies. A 'persistent' cookie will remain for a period of time set for that cookie. A 'session-based' cookie is allocated only for the duration of your visit to our website and automatically expires when you close down your browser.

First-party cookies

First-party cookies originate from the same domain as the website you’re currently visiting (in this case, vodafone.co.uk).  
See our list of first-party cookies (shown later on in this cookies policy).

Third-party cookies are not used in association with the OneNumber website.

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| What it’s called | What it’s used for | Type | Duration |
| First party cookies |     |     |     |
| smck | Contains the list of all user's msisdns and the one selected to be used for the login and portal operations | 1   | 30 days (unless user logs out) |
| mduser | Contains the auth token received from the backend | 1   | expires after session |
| auth\_redirection | Set before the login phase and contains the page that the user tried to see in order to redirect her/him to that page after the login | 1   | expires after session |
| auth\_infos | Used to remember which client ID the FE needs to proceed with the login process | 1   | expires after session |
| X-B3-TraceId | Random value generated by the client device for every session, it's used to track the user navigation on the portal | 2   | expires after session |
| smapiInfos | Contains some information used by Vodafone to check user navigation and send problems | 2   | expires after session |
| smapi\_subject\_id | Set by Vodafone analytics library | 2   | 24 months |
| smapi\_session\_id | Set by Vodafone analytics library | 2   | expires after session |
| smapi\_install\_id | Set by Vodafone analytics library | 2   | 24 months |
| primary\_msisdns | Contains the list of all user's msisdns and the verified primary numbers to be used for the login and portal operations | 2   | 30 days |

Controlling your cookies  
You can manage your cookie preferences by accessing the preference centre below;

Consent Preferences  
You can also control how you use cookies in your browser or your device settings. Information on controlling and deleting cookies is also available at [http://allaboutcookies.org](http://allaboutcookies.org/)

### v.vodafone.com – Privacy statement

V by Vodafone – Privacy Statement

This privacy statement explains the information that is collected by Vodafone through the connectivity services we provide to your Connected Devices (‘Connected Devices’) and how this data will be processed. Connected Devices are those that are compatible with a V-Sim. You can view this statement, and the statement for our Connected Devices in the Settings Menu of the App at any time.

Some of our products are developed in partnership with specific third party partners, who will process your personal data as a data controller in their own right.

*   V-Pet, in partnership with [Kippy](https://www.kippy.eu/) or POD
    
*   V-Bag and V-Kids Watch in partnership with Alcatel
    
*   V-Camera, in partnership with [Arlo](http://netgear.com/about/privacy-policy/).
    
*   V-Luggage and V-Mini, in partnership with [Trackimo](https://trackimo.com/).

We take the privacy of our users very seriously. We ask that you read this privacy statement carefully as it contains important information about how we will use your personal data.

Changes to our privacy policy

This Privacy Policy gets updated from time to time; whenever we make a change, we’ll update the content and let you know.

We have recently revised our Privacy Statement for this App and Service; the main changes are listed below.

| Section | Changes |
| --- | --- |
| Reformatted privacy notice | We have updated the structure and format of the privacy notice to meet new legal requirements. |
| Added new partners | We have added new links to our additional partners for our newly launched products. |

Who we are  

We are Vodafone Ireland Ltd, a member of the Vodafone Group.  

In this privacy policy:

*   “we/us” means Vodafone Ireland Ltd.;
    
*   “third party” means someone who is not you or us; and
    
*   “Vodafone Group” means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital.

Our registered office is Vodafone Ireland, Mountain View, Leopardstown, Dublin 18. We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

Our main switchboard is +353 1 2037000.

How to contact us

Your opinion matters to us – if you have any questions about our privacy policy, you can email us at: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or you can write to our privacy team at:

Data Protection Officer  
Vodafone Ireland  
Mountain View  
Leopardstown  
Dublin 18  
Ireland

### Personal information we collect about you

Information we collect about you

The types of information we process about you when you use your Connected Devices are:

*   Your Connected Device-generated data where it’s been provided by our partners (see Third party sources of data);
    
*   Your account information, such as the number of products you have with us and dates of payment owed or received;
    
*   Your preferences for particular products or services when you tell us what they are, or we assume what they are, based on how you use the products and services (see Marketing & profiling);
    
*   Customer care information through your contact with us, such as a note or recording of a call you make to one of our contact centres;
    
*   Information about the V-Sim connectivity we provide for Connected Devices, such as the data connections performed and the amount of data consumed;
    
*   Your location data. This can be precise where it uses Global Positioning System (GPS) data or by identifying nearby mobile phone masts and Wi-Fi hotspots. Or less precise where, for example, a location is derived from your IP address or data such as a post code or name of a town or city.

We’ll also get information about how you use our products and services, such as:

*   The level of service that you receive – for example, network or service faults and other events that may affect our network services or other services; and
    
*   Details of your use of our services – for example, we can see the amount of data your devices are using which we can use to assess what sorts of data allowances we need to provide for different Connected Devices.

When we collect your personal information

We collect your personal information when:

*   You use any of your Connected Devices;
    
*   Device or app-generated data has been provided by our partners (see Third party sources of data);
    
*   You subscribe to marketing; or
    
*   You contact our customer care teams with a question or complaint.

Third party sources of data

Given that our customer care teams act of your one-stop-shop for queries and issues around your Connected Devices, we share limited personal data between Vodafone and the partners whose products you have purchased in order for us to achieve this. For example, we may need to share the fact that your device isn’t working or that we needed to reset it with the partner in question.

If you have given us your permission, we also receive your Connected Device’s Service Data from our partners in order to profile you and tailor our communications to you. For example, if we can see that you regularly use a product we might think you want to hear about our others. You can adjust your privacy preferences at any time; see Marketing and profiling for more details.

Where necessary, we collect information from certain organisations. These include fraud-prevention agencies, business directories and credit reference agencies.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

1\. The performance of your contract or to enter into the contract and to take action on your requests. For example, we’ll need to process your network traffic data as part of making your devices “connected” and we’ll need to process your payment details for your monthly billing.

2\. Vodafone’s legitimate business interests, for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, direct marketing, and improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the Your Rights section of this policy.

3\. Compliance with a mandatory legal obligation, including for example accounting and tax requirements, which are subject to strict internal policies (such as retention periods), procedures, and your right to restrict usage of your data, which control the scope of legal assistance to be provided; or

4\. Consent you provide where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis. Consent is always presented to you separately and you can withdraw your consent at any time.

### How we use your personal information

1\. To provide you with your service

We use your information for service provision and to fulfil any purchases you have made:

*   to help us identify you and any accounts you hold with us;
    
*   to provide you with the connectivity you have requested for your Connected Devices;
    
*   billing and customer care; and
    
*   identity verification.

2\. Marketing & profiling

If you are opted into marketing and have given us permission to use your data to tailor these communications, we’ll use your purchasing preferences and data from your Connected Devices to inform the sorts of marketing we should be sending you so that it’s the most relevant for you. For example, if we can see that you have purchased V-Pet, we can make sure we don’t market that product to you.

To opt out of Marketing messages or profiling:

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, messaging, phone or post).

There are various ways to opt out:

*   If you are a Vodafone consumer mobile customer, you can log in to your My Vodafone account, access ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App, or call 1800 200 234 to manage your marketing permissions and to opt out or into receiving personalised marketing.
    
*   For customers without a Vodafone mobile number, you can manage your permissions in the V by Vodafone App.
    
*   Contact our customer services team via v.vodafone.com;
    
*   All our marketing messages come with an “unsubscribe” link which you can click to unsubscribe;
    
*   Tell the adviser if you receive an outbound marketing call;
    
*   Email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for guidance.

Opting out does not mean that you won’t any longer receive service-related messages, such as messages telling you about your order status or when our Terms & Conditions change. You will still continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise).

3\. Other profiling and automated processing

Outside of the profiling we conduct for marketing purposes to tailor and personalise the communications we send, we also profile you for credit, fraud and security purposes.

This can sometimes use systems to make automated decisions based on personal information we have or are allowed to collect from others. The goal is to make the decisions as quick, efficient, fair and correct as possible, based on what we know. It can affect the products or services we may offer you now or in the future.

We will process your personal data in order to protect against and detect fraud, and to recover debts or trace those who owe us money resulting from the use of our services.

4\. Service improvement

*   We collect anonymous, de-identified or aggregate information in order to improve the service we offer to everyone. None of these analytics are linked back to you in any way.
    
*   To protect our networks and manage the volumes of calls, texts and other uses of our networks. For example, we identify peak periods of use so we can try and ensure the networks can handle the volume at those times; and
    
*   To understand how you use our networks, products and services. That way we can seek to review, develop and improve these, develop more interesting and relevant products and services, as well as personalising our products and services.

### How we share your personal information

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group;
    
*   Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used;
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Limited, or Vodafone Group;
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law; or
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.

We also share aggregate performance information with third party V by Vodafone partners to understand how products and the V by Vodafone offering is performing commercially. For example, if we know that certain products are selling well, we can focus on partnering with more partners that cater to the market. This information does not identify you personally.

### International data transfers

If you are a non-Vodafone consumer mobile customer and we need to verify your identity, we will need to transfer your data to our service provider, which is based in India. Additionally our customer care centres are run by Vodafone Shared Services which is based in Hungary, Egypt, India and Romania.

When Vodafone sends your information to a country that is not in the EEA, we make sure that your information is properly protected. We will always ensure that there is a proper legal agreement that covers the data transfer. In addition, if the country is not considered to have laws that are equivalent to EU data protection standards then we will ask the third party to enter into a legal agreement that reflects those standards.

### How long we keep your personal information

We’ll store and process your information for as long as we have to by law or as long as we need to be able to deliver you the services you have requested. We’ll keep some personal information for a reasonable period after your contract with us has finished in case you decide to use our services again. We, or one of our partners, may contact you about Vodafone services during this time if you haven’t opted out of receiving marketing communications from us. Once these bases have expired, we’ll delete that information.

### Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as emails) aren’t secure unless they’ve been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.  

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.  

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.  

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.  

The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.  

You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including those offered by Google, Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) or using third-party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information.  

Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies. You should make sure you’re familiar with these.

### Your rights

Below we set out details on how you can exercise your rights. If you have a question or cannot find the answer, please contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com.

Right to correct personal data  
If you become aware that any of the information we keep about you is incorrect or outdated, you can log into your My Vodafone account to edit your personal details. Alternatively, please contact customer care on 1907.

Right to access personal data  
If you are a current customer and would like a copy of your personal data, you can submit your request by logging into your My Vodafone account. If you are not an active customer, please send your request to [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) including details of the account in question or any accounts you have previously had.

We will confirm receipt of your request and ensure that you receive this information within one month of the date of your request.

Right to data portability  
You can submit a portability request by this by logging into your My Vodafone account.  
You will receive your information in a digital, machine-readable format.

Right to object to use of personal data

*   If you do not want your personal information to be used for any purpose, other than those necessary to provide a service to you, please let us know by selecting your data preferences. You can change your preferences at any time using your My Vodafone account. By selecting ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App or by calling 1800 200 234. For customers without a Vodafone mobile number, you can manage your permissions in the V by Vodafone App.

How to lodge a complaint

If you want to contact us about any of your rights, or to enquire or make a complaint about how we use your information, contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com or by email at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) We’ll do our best to help but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact Data Protection Commission. Contact details for the Data Protection Commissioner are:

*   Email: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
    
*   Phone: +353 (0)57 868 4757 or +353 (0)761 104 800
    
*   In writing: Data Protection Office, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, County Laois, R32 AP23, or Data Protection Office, 21 Fitzwilliam Square, Dublin 2, D02 RD28.

Right to restrict use of your data  
If you wish to restrict the use of your data by Vodafone, please email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). It is helpful to let us know the reason for your restriction request.

Right to erasure

If you would like us to remove your personal data from our records, you can request this by logging into your My Vodafone account. If you do not have an active account, please email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to let us know what information you would like to have deleted.

We will send you confirmation when your request has been completed. Please note that if you have an active service with us, much of the information that we keep about you cannot be deleted as this is required to provide you with the service to you and to provide support to you.

### V by Vodafone eShop

This privacy statement (‘Statement’) explains the information that is collected by Vodafone when you use this website and purchase products and services through our online store. You can view the privacy statements for our connected products within their respective apps.

Our website contains links to other websites. This privacy statement applies only to this website so when you access links to other websites you should read their own privacy policies.

We take the privacy of our users very seriously. We ask that you read this privacy statement carefully as it contains important information about how we will use your personal data.

### Changes to our privacy policy

This Privacy Policy gets updated from time to time; whenever we make a change, we’ll update the content and we’ll communicate any material changes.  

We have recently revised our Privacy Statement for this website; the main changes are listed below.  

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Section | Changes |
| Reformatted privacy notice & updated cookie notice | We have updated the structure and format of the privacy notice to meet new legal requirements and updated our cookie notice to cover new cookies deployed on the site. |

Who we are We are Vodafone Ireland Ltd, a member of the Vodafone Group.

In this privacy policy:

*   “we/us” means Vodafone Ireland Ltd.;
    
*   “third party” means someone who is not you or us; and
    
*   “Vodafone Group” means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital.

Our registered office is Vodafone Ireland, Mountain View, Leopardstown, Dublin 18. We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

Our main switchboard is +353 1 2037000.

How to contact us

Your opinion matters to us – if you have any questions about our privacy policy, you can email us at: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or you can write to our privacy team at:

Data Protection Officer Vodafone Ireland Mountain View Leopardstown Dublin 18 Ireland

Personal information we collect about you

Information we collect about you

The types of information we process about you when you use this site are:

*   Your contact details, such as name, address, phone number, and email address;
    
*   Your payment details, such as credit or debit card information and banking information;
    
*   The types of products you have purchased;
    
*   Any contact you have with us such as calls to us or if you email us; and
    
*   Your website browsing information, such as how you are using our website or your IP address.

When we collect your personal information

We can collect your personal data when you:

*   Visit or browse this website;
    
*   Purchase products and services from us;
    
*   Register your interest for future products and services; or
    
*   Contact us with a complaint or query.

Third party sources of data

Where necessary, we collect information from certain organisations. These include fraud-prevention agencies, business directories and credit reference agencies.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

1\. The performance of your contract or to enter into the contract and to take action on your requests. For example, we’ll need to process your payment details and billing address to be able to fulfil your purchase and send you your hardware.

2\. Vodafone’s legitimate business interests, for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, direct marketing, and improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the Your Rights section of this policy.

3\. Compliance with a mandatory legal obligation, including for example accounting and tax requirements, which are subject to strict internal policies (such as retention periods), procedures, and your right to restrict usage of your data, which control the scope of legal assistance to be provided; or

4\. Consent you provide where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis. Consent is always presented to you separately and you can withdraw your consent at any time.

How we use your personal information

1\. To provide you with your service

We use your information for service provision and to fulfil any purchases you have made:

*   To process the products and services you’ve bought from us, and keep you updated with the progress of your order;
    
*   To bill you for using our products and services, or to take the appropriate amount of credit from you;
    
*   Contact you if the billing information you provided us with is about to expire or we’re not able to take payment;
    
*   To respond to any questions or concerns you may have about our network, products or services; and
    
*   We will contact you with customer service messages to keep you updated with current information about products and services you’ve purchased. For example, changes to our terms and conditions, or letting you know about the status of your order.

2\. Marketing and profiling

If you are opted into marketing and given us permission to use your data to tailor these communications, we’ll use your interactions with this site to inform the sorts of marketing we should be sending you so that it’s the most relevant for you. For example, if we can see that you have purchased V-Pet, we can make sure we don’t market that product to you.

To opt out of Marketing messages or profiling:

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, messaging, phone or post).

There are various ways to opt out:

*   If you are a Vodafone consumer mobile customer, you can log in to your My Vodafone account, access ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App, or call 1800 200 234 to manage your marketing permissions and to opt out or into receiving personalised marketing.
    
*   For customers without a Vodafone mobile number, you can manage your permissions in the V by Vodafone App.
    
*   Contact our customer services team via v.vodafone.com;
    
*   All our marketing messages come with an “unsubscribe” link which you can click to unsubscribe;
    
*   Tell the adviser if you receive an outbound marketing call;
    
*   Email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for guidance.

Opting out does not mean that you won’t any longer receive service-related messages, such as messages telling you about your order status or when our Terms & Conditions change. You will still continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise).

3\. Other profiling

Outside of the profiling we conduct for marketing purposes to tailor and personalise the communications we send, we also profile you for credit, fraud and security purposes.

This can sometimes use systems to make automated decisions based on personal information we have or are allowed to collect from others. The goal is to make the decisions as quick, efficient, fair and correct as possible, based on what we know. It can affect the products or services we may offer you now or in the future.

*   We will carry out a credit check when you apply for a contract for your products and services with us. Information on credit checks is included in our [Privacy Policy](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy).
    
*   If you are not already a Vodafone customer, we will use your personal information for identity verification purposes. We sometimes supplement the information we collect about you with information from other sources (such as the electoral roll) This will be prompted to you on first registration of a connected device within the V by Vodafone or V Auto apps. We also use this verification for access to your account and for general account management. However, this identity verification process is supported by human agents that will verify the output of the automated decision.
    
*   We will process your personal data in order to protect against and detect fraud, and to recover debts or trace those who owe us money resulting from the use of our services.

How we share your personal information

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group;
    
*   Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used;
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Ireland Limited, or Vodafone Group;
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law; or
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.

We also share aggregate performance information with third party V by Vodafone partners to understand how products and the V by Vodafone offering is performing commercially. For example, if we know that certain products are selling well, we can focus on delivering more of the same. This information does not identify you personally.

International data transfers

We may need to transfer your information to other Vodafone Group companies or service providers in countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). The EEA consists of countries in the European Union, Switzerland, Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway: they are considered to have equivalent laws when it comes to data protection and privacy. This kind of data transfer may happen if our servers (i.e. where we store data) or our suppliers and service providers are based outside the EEA, or if you use our services and products while visiting countries outside this area.

If Vodafone sends your information to a country that is not in the EEA, we will make sure that your information is properly protected. We will always ensure that there is a proper legal agreement that covers the data transfer. In addition, if the country is not considered to have laws that are equivalent to EU data protection standards then we will ask the third party to enter into a legal agreement that reflects those standards.

How long we keep your personal information for

We’ll store and process your information for as long as we have to by law or as long as we need to be able to deliver you the services you have requested. We’ll keep some personal information for a reasonable period after your contract with us has finished in case you decide to use our services again. We, or one of our partners, may contact you about Vodafone services during this time if you haven’t opted out of receiving marketing communications from us. Once these bases have expired, we’ll delete that information.

Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as emails) aren’t secure unless they’ve been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.

The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.

You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including those offered by Google, Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) or using third-party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information.

Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies. You should make sure you’re familiar with these.

Your rights

Below we set out details on how you can exercise your rights. If you have a question or cannot find the answer, please contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com.

Right to correct personal data If you become aware that any of the information we keep about you is incorrect or outdated, you can log into your My Vodafone account to edit your personal details. Alternatively, please contact customer care on 1907.

Right to access personal data If you are a current customer and would like a copy of your personal data, you can submit your request by logging into your My Vodafone account. If you are not an active customer, please send your request to [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) including details of the account in question or any accounts you have previously had.

We will confirm receipt of your request and ensure that you receive this information within one month of the date of your request.

Right to data portability You can submit a portability request by this by logging into your My Vodafone account.

You will receive your information in a digital, machine-readable format.

Right to object to use of personal data

*   If you do not want your personal information to be used for any purpose, other than those necessary to provide a service to you, please let us know by selecting your data preferences. You can change your preferences at any time using your My Vodafone account. By selecting ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App or by calling 1800 200 234. For customers without a Vodafone mobile number, you can manage your permissions in the V by Vodafone App.

How to lodge a complaint

If you want to contact us about any of your rights, or to enquire or make a complaint about how we use your information, contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com or by email at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) We’ll do our best to help but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact Data Protection Commission. Contact details for the Data Protection Commissioner are:

*   Email: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
    
*   Phone: +353 (0)57 868 4757 or +353 (0)761 104 800
    
*   In writing: Data Protection Office, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, County Laois, R32 AP23, or Data Protection Office, 21 Fitzwilliam Square, Dublin 2, D02 RD28.

Right to restrict use of your data

If you wish to restrict the use of your data by Vodafone, please email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). It is helpful to let us know the reason for your restriction request.

Right to erasure

If you would like us to remove your personal data from our records, you can request this by logging into your My Vodafone account. If you do not have an active account, please email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to let us know what information you would like to have deleted.

We will send you confirmation when your request has been completed. Please note that if you have an active service with us, much of the information that we keep about you cannot be deleted as this is required to provide you with the service to you and to provide support to you.

Our cookie policy

A cookie is a small text file which is placed onto your mobile (or other electronic device) when you access our website. More information also available at https://www.vodafone.ie/content?id=BAU026375&v=2

The table below is designed to provide more information about the cookies we use and why:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Name of cookie | Owner | Purpose of the cookie |
| utag\_main | Tealium | Anonymously gathers usage statistics. |
| cart\_vodafoneiotuk | Vodafone | Holds your shopping cart details. |
| Vodafoneredirect | Vodafone | A tracking cookie from the shop which holds generic browsing information. |
| IDGW | Vodafone | A temporary cookie when using Vodafone ID. No personal-identifiable information is stored. The cookie expires when the session ends. |
| IDP | Vodafone | A temporary cookie when using Vodafone ID. No personal-identifiable information is stored. The cookie expires when the session ends. |
| cookie\_policy | Vodafone | This stores that you have accepted the cookie policy. |

### V by Vodafone cellular products

This privacy statement explains the information that is collected by Vodafone through the connectivity services we provide to your Connected Devices (‘Connected Devices’) and how this data will be processed. Connected Devices are those that are compatible with a V-Sim. You can view this statement, and the statement for our Connected Devices in the Settings Menu of the App at any time.

Some of our products are developed in partnership with specific third party partners, who will process your personal data as a data controller in their own right.

*   V-Pet, in partnership with [Kippy](https://www.kippy.eu/)or POD
    
*   V-Bag and V-Kids Watch in partnership with Alcatel.
    
*   V-Camera, in partnership with [Arlo](http://netgear.com/about/privacy-policy/).
    
*   V-Luggage and V-Multi Tracker in partnership with [Trackimo](https://trackimo.com/).

We take the privacy of our users very seriously. We ask that you read this privacy statement carefully as it contains important information about how we will use your personal data.

Changes to our privacy policy

This Privacy Policy gets updated from time to time; whenever we make a change, we’ll update the content and let you know.

We have recently revised our Privacy Statement for this App and Service; the main changes are listed below.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Section | Changes |
| Reformatted privacy notice | We have updated the structure and format of the privacy notice to meet new legal requirements. |
| Added new partners | We have added new links to our additional partners for our newly launched products. |
|     |     |

Last updated: \[05/11/2018\]

Who we are

We are Vodafone Ireland Ltd, a member of the Vodafone Group.

In this privacy policy:

*   “we/us”means Vodafone Ireland Ltd.;
    
*   “third party”means someone who is not you or us; and
    
*   “Vodafone Group”means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital.

Our registered office is Vodafone Ireland, Mountain View, Leopardstown, Dublin 18. We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

Our main switchboard is +353 1 2037000.

How to contact us

Your opinion matters to us –if you have any questions about our privacy policy, you can email us at: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or you can write to our privacy team at:

Data Protection Officer Vodafone Ireland Mountain View Leopardstown Dublin 18 Ireland

Personal information we collect about you

Information we collect about you

The types of information we process about you when you use your Connected Devices are:

*   Your Connected Device-generated data where it’s been provided by our partners (see Third party sources of data);
    
*   Your account information, such as the number of products you have with us and dates of payment owed or received;
    
*   Your preferences for particular products or services when you tell us what they are, or we assume what they are, based on how you use the products and services (see Marketing & profiling);
    
*   Customer care information through your contact with us, such as a note or recording of a call you make to one of our contact centres;
    
*   Information about the V-Sim connectivity we provide for Connected Devices, such as the data connections performed and the amount of data consumed;
    
*   Your location data. This can be precise where it uses Global Positioning System (GPS) data or by identifying nearby mobile phone masts and Wi-Fi hotspots. Or less precise where, for example, a location is derived from your IP address or data such as a post code or name of a town or city.

We’ll also get information about how you use our products and services, such as:

*   The level of service that you receive – for example, network or service faults and other events that may affect our network services or other services; and
    
*   Details of your use of our services – for example, we can see the amount of data your devices are using which we can use to assess what sorts of data allowances we need to provide for different Connected Devices.

When we collect your personal information

We collect your personal information when:

*   You use any of your Connected Devices;
    
*   Device or app-generated data has been provided by our partners (see Third party sources of data);
    
*   You subscribe to marketing; or
    
*   You contact our customer care teams with a question or complaint.

Third party sources of data

Given that our customer care teams act of your one-stop-shop for queries and issues around your Connected Devices, we share limited personal data between Vodafone and the partners whose products you have purchased in order for us to achieve this. For example, we may need to share the fact that your device isn’t working or that we needed to reset it with the partner in question.

If you have given us your permission, we also receive your Connected Device’s Service Data from our partners in order to profile you and tailor our communications to you. For example, if we can see that you regularly use a product we might think you want to hear about our others. You can adjust your privacy preferences at any time; see Marketing and profiling for more details.

Where necessary, we collect information from certain organisations. These include fraud-prevention agencies, business directories and credit reference agencies.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

1\. The performance of your contract or to enter into the contract and to take action on your requests. For example, we’ll need to process your network traffic data as part of making your devices “connected” and we’ll need to process your payment details for your monthly billing.

2\. Vodafone’s legitimate business interests, for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, direct marketing, and improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases, you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the Your Rights section of this policy.

3\. Compliance with a mandatory legal obligation, including for example accounting and tax requirements, which are subject to strict internal policies (such as retention periods), procedures, and your right to restrict usage of your data, which control the scope of legal assistance to be provided; or

4\. Consent you provide where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis. Consent is always presented to you separately and you can withdraw your consent at any time.

How we use your personal information

1\. To provide you with your service

We use your information for service provision and to fulfil any purchases you have made:

*   to help us identify you and any accounts you hold with us;
    
*   to provide you with the connectivity you have requested for your Connected Devices;
    
*   billing and customer care; and
    
*   identity verification.

2\. Marketing & profiling

If you are opted into marketing and have given us permission to use your data to tailor these communications, we’ll use your purchasing preferences and data from your Connected Devices to inform the sorts of marketing we should be sending you so that it’s the most relevant for you. For example, if we can see that you have purchased V-Pet, we can make sure we don’t market that product to you.

To opt out of Marketing messages or profiling:

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, messaging, phone or post).

There are various ways to opt out:

*   If you are a Vodafone consumer mobile customer, you can log in to your My Vodafone account, access ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App, or call 1800 200 234 to manage your marketing permissions and to opt out or into receiving personalised marketing.
    
*   For customers without a Vodafone mobile number, you can manage your permissions in the V by Vodafone App.
    
*   Contact our customer services team via v.vodafone.com;
    
*   All our marketing messages come with an “unsubscribe” link which you can click to unsubscribe;
    
*   Tell the adviser if you receive an outbound marketing call;
    
*   Email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for guidance.

Opting out does not mean that you won’t any longer receive service-related messages, such as messages telling you about your order status or when our Terms & Conditions change. You will still continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise).

3\. Other profiling and automated processing

Outside of the profiling we conduct for marketing purposes to tailor and personalise the communications we send, we also profile you for credit, fraud and security purposes.

This can sometimes use systems to make automated decisions based on personal information we have or are allowed to collect from others. The goal is to make the decisions as quick, efficient, fair and correct as possible, based on what we know. It can affect the products or services we may offer you now or in the future.

We will process your personal data in order to protect against and detect fraud, and to recover debts or trace those who owe us money resulting from the use of our services.

4\. Service improvement

*   We collect anonymous, de-identified or aggregate information in order to improve the service we offer to everyone. None of these analytics are linked back to you in any way.
    
*   To protect our networks and manage the volumes of calls, texts and other uses of our networks. For example, we identify peak periods of use so we can try and ensure the networks can handle the volume at those times; and
    
*   To understand how you use our networks, products and services. That way we can seek to review, develop and improve these, develop more interesting and relevant products and services, as well as personalising our products and services.

How we share your personal information

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group;
    
*   Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used;
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Limited, or Vodafone Group;
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law; or
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.

We also share aggregate performance information with third party V by Vodafone partners to understand how products and the V by Vodafone offering is performing commercially. For example, if we know that certain products are selling well, we can focus on partnering with more partners that cater to the market. This information does not identify you personally.

\[ACCORDION\] International data transfers

If you are a non-Vodafone consumer mobile customer and we need to verify your identity, we will need to transfer your data to our service provider, which is based in India. Additionally our customer care centres are run by Vodafone Shared Services which is based in Hungary, Egypt, India and Romania.

When Vodafone sends your information to a country that is not in the EEA, we make sure that your information is properly protected. We will always ensure that there is a proper legal agreement that covers the data transfer. In addition, if the country is not considered to have laws that are equivalent to EU data protection standards then we will ask the third party to enter into a legal agreement that reflects those standards.

How long we keep your personal information for

We’ll store and process your information for as long as we have to by law or as long as we need to be able to deliver you the services you have requested. We’ll keep some personal information for a reasonable period after your contract with us has finished in case you decide to use our services again. We, or one of our partners, may contact you about Vodafone services during this time if you haven’t opted out of receiving marketing communications from us. Once these bases have expired, we’ll delete that information.

Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as emails) aren’t secure unless they’ve been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.

The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.

You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including those offered by Google, Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) or using third-party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information.

Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies. You should make sure you’re familiar with these.

Your rights

Below we set out details on how you can exercise your rights. If you have a question or cannot find the answer, please contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com.

Right to correct personal data If you become aware that any of the information we keep about you is incorrect or outdated, you can log into your My Vodafone account to edit your personal details. Alternatively, please contact customer care on 1907.

Right to access personal data If you are a current customer and would like a copy of your personal data, you can submit your request by logging into your My Vodafone account. If you are not an active customer, please send your request to [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) including details of the account in question or any accounts you have previously had.

We will confirm receipt of your request and ensure that you receive this information within one month of the date of your request.

Right to data portability You can submit a portability request by this by logging into your My Vodafone account. You will receive your information in a digital, machine-readable format.

Right to object to use of personal data · If you do not want your personal information to be used for any purpose, other than those necessary to provide a service to you, please let us know by selecting your data preferences. You can change your preferences at any time using your My Vodafone account. By selecting ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App or by calling 1800 200 234. For customers without a Vodafone mobile number, you can manage your permissions in the V by Vodafone App.

How to lodge a complaint

If you want to contact us about any of your rights, or to enquire or make a complaint about how we use your information, contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com or by email at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) We’ll do our best to help but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact Data Protection Commission. Contact details for the Data Protection Commissioner are:

*   Email: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
    
*   Phone: +353 (0)57 868 4757 or +353 (0)761 104 800
    
*   In writing: Data Protection Office, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, County Laois, R32 AP23, or Data Protection Office, 21 Fitzwilliam Square, Dublin 2, D02 RD28.

Right to restrict use of your data If you wish to restrict the use of your data by Vodafone, please email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). It is helpful to let us know the reason for your restriction request.

Right to erasure

If you would like us to remove your personal data from our records, you can request this by logging into your My Vodafone account. If you do not have an active account, please email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to let us know what information you would like to have deleted.

We will send you confirmation when your request has been completed. Please note that if you have an active service with us, much of the information that we keep about you cannot be deleted as this is required to provide you with the service to you and to provide support to you.

### V-App

This privacy statement explains the information that is collected by Vodafone through the V by Vodafone application (‘App’). We have privacy statements for our respective Connected Devices that we will present to you as you add a new device to your account. You can view this statement, and the statement for our Connected Devices in the Settings Menu of the App at any time.  

### Changes to our privacy policy

This Privacy Policy gets updated from time to time; whenever we make a change, we’ll update the content and let you know.  

We have recently revised our Privacy Statement for this App and Service; the main changes are listed below.  

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Section | Changes |
| Reformatted privacy notice | We have updated the structure and format of the privacy notice to meet new legal requirements. |

Who we are

We are Vodafone Ireland Ltd, a member of the Vodafone Group.

In this privacy policy:

*   “we/us” means Vodafone Ireland Ltd.;
    
*   “third party” means someone who is not you or us; and
    
*   “Vodafone Group” means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital.

Our registered office is Vodafone Ireland, Mountain View, Leopardstown, Dublin 18. We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

Our main switchboard is +353 1 2037000.

How to contact us

Your opinion matters to us – if you have any questions about our privacy policy, you can email us at: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or you can write to our privacy team at:

Data Protection Officer

Vodafone Ireland

Mountain View

Leopardstown

Dublin 18

Ireland

Personal information we collect about you

Address Book

When our customers upload their address book to the V by Vodafone App, we collect your information. You will receive an SMS alert if they subsequently add you as a Trusted Contact for one of our V Products.

We will receive the following information about you:

*   Your mobile phone number;
    
*   Your full name; and
    
*   (If provided) your relationship to our customer (for example, mother or spouse)

We will not use your data for purposes other than adding them to services when requested by the account holder.

You can remove yourself as a Trusted Contact at any time by either:

*   Asking our customer to remove you from their list;
    
*   Asking an agent when you are contacted (please quote the ID provided in your SMS alert); or
    
*   Request removal via customer services via v.vodafone.com.

Information we collect about you

The types of information we process about you when you use your V by Vodafone App are:

*   Your name, address, mobile number, date of birth and email address;
    
*   If we need to verify your identity, documentation such as a passport or other identification;
    
*   Your account information, such as the number of connected SIMs you have with us and dates of payment owed or received;
    
*   Your credential information such as passwords, hints and similar security information used for authentication and access to accounts and services;
    
*   Any photos you upload to personalise your Connected Devices’ accounts;
    
*   Your preferences for particular products or services when you tell us what they are, or we assume what they are, based on how you use the products and services (see Marketing & profiling);
    
*   Customer care information through your contact with us, such as a note or recording of a call you make to one of our contact centres;
    
*   Information about your mobile device each time you use the App. For example, we may collect information on the type of mobile device that you are using and its unique device identifier (for example, the IMEI number, the device’s mobile phone number, or the MAC address of the device’s wireless network interface);
    
*   Information about your usage of the App, such as how often you use it; and
    
*   Your location data. This can be precise where it uses Global Positioning System (GPS) data or by identifying nearby mobile phone masts and Wi-Fi hotspots. Or less precise where, for example, a location is derived from your IP address or data such as a post code or name of a town or city.

We’ll also get information about how you use our products and services, such as:

*   The level of service that you receive – for example, network or service faults and other events that may affect our network services or other services;
    
*   Details of your use of our services – for example, we can see the amount of data your devices are using which we can use to assess what sorts of data allowances we need to provide for different Connected Devices; and
    
*   We also collect anonymous analytics information on how our customers use the V by Vodafone App in order to improve your experience and troubleshoot.

When we collect your personal information

We collect your personal information when:

*   You buy a connected product from us (online, or in store);
    
*   You first register your Connected Device product in the V by Vodafone App;
    
*   If you’re a non-Vodafone customer, when we verify your identity and you add your payment details;
    
*   You grant the App access to your camera (for taking pictures for ID verification) or your device’s photo album (if you want to add personalised pictures to your Connected Devices’ accounts);
    
*   You use the V by Vodafone Application; or
    
*   You subscribe to marketing.

Third party sources of data

Where necessary, we collect information from certain organisations. These include fraud-prevention agencies, business directories and credit reference agencies.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

1\. The performance of your contract or to enter into the contract and to take action on your requests. For example, we’ll need to process your payment details for your monthly billing.

2\. Vodafone’s legitimate business interests, for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, direct marketing, and improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the Your Rights section of this policy.

3\. Compliance with a mandatory legal obligation, including for example accounting and tax requirements, which are subject to strict internal policies (such as retention periods), procedures, and your right to restrict usage of your data, which control the scope of legal assistance to be provided; or

4\. Consent you provide where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis. Consent is always presented to you separately and you can withdraw your consent at any time.

How we use your personal information

1\. To provide you with your service

We use your information for service provision and to fulfil any purchases you have made:

*   to help us identify you and any accounts you hold with us;
    
*   billing and customer care;
    
*   to notify you of any changes to the App or to our services that may affect you; and
    
*   identity verification.

2\. Marketing & profiling

If you are opted into marketing and given us permission to use your data to tailor these communications, we’ll use your interactions with this App and data from your Connected Devices to inform the sorts of marketing we should be sending you so that it’s the most relevant for you.

To opt out of Marketing messages or profiling:

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, messaging, phone or post).

There are various ways to opt out:

*   If you are a Vodafone consumer mobile customer, you can log in to your My Vodafone account, access ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App, or call 1800 200 234 to manage your marketing permissions and to opt out or into receiving personalised marketing.
    
*   For customers without a Vodafone mobile number, you can manage your permissions in the V by Vodafone App.
    
*   Contact our customer services team via v.vodafone.com;
    
*   All our marketing messages come with an “unsubscribe” link which you can click to unsubscribe;
    
*   Tell the adviser if you receive an outbound marketing call;
    
*   Email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for guidance.

Opting out does not mean that you won’t any longer receive service-related messages, such as messages telling you about your order status or when our Terms & Conditions change. You will still continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise).

3\. Other profiling and automated processing

Outside of the profiling we conduct for marketing purposes to tailor and personalise the communications we send, we also profile you for credit, fraud and security purposes.

This can sometimes use systems to make automated decisions based on personal information we have or are allowed to collect from others. The goal is to make the decisions as quick, efficient, fair and correct as possible, based on what we know. It can affect the products or services we may offer you now or in the future.

*   We will carry out a credit check when you apply for a contract for your products and services with us. Information on credit checks is included in our [Privacy Policy](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy).
    
*   If you are not already a Vodafone customer, we will use your personal information for identity verification purposes. We sometimes supplement the information we collect about you with information from other sources (such as the electoral roll). This will be prompted to you on first registration of a connected device within the V by Vodafone or V Auto apps. We also use this verification for access to your account and for general account management. However, this identity verification process is supported by human agents that will verify the output of the automated decision.
    
*   We will process your personal data in order to protect against and detect fraud, and to recover debts or trace those who owe us money resulting from the use of our services.

4\. Service improvement

*   We collect anonymous, de-identified or aggregate information in order to improve the service we offer to everyone. None of these analytics are linked back to you in any way.
    
*   To protect our networks and manage the volumes of calls, texts and other uses of our networks. For example, we identify peak periods of use so we can try and ensure the networks can handle the volume at those times; and
    
*   To understand how you use our networks, products and services. That way we can seek to review, develop and improve these, develop more interesting and relevant products and services, as well as personalising our products and services.

How we share your personal information

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group;
    
*   Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used;
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Ireland Limited, or Vodafone Group;
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law; or
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.

We also share aggregate performance information with third party V by Vodafone partners to understand how products and the V by Vodafone offering is performing commercially. For example, if we know that certain products are selling well, we can focus on partnering with more partners that cater to the market. This information does not identify you personally.

International data transfers

If you are a non-Vodafone customer and we need to verify your identity, we will need to transfer your data to our service provider, which is based in India. Additionally our customer care centres are run by Vodafone Shared Services which is based in Hungary, Egypt, India and Romania.

When Vodafone sends your information to a country that is not in the EEA, we make sure that your information is properly protected. We will always ensure that there is a proper legal agreement that covers the data transfer. In addition, if the country is not considered to have laws that are equivalent to EU data protection standards then we will ask the third party to enter into a legal agreement that reflects those standards.

How long we keep your personal information for

We’ll store and process your information for as long as we have to by law or as long as we need to be able to deliver you the services you have requested. We’ll keep some personal information for a reasonable period after your contract with us has finished in case you decide to use our services again. We, or one of our partners, may contact you about Vodafone services during this time if you haven’t opted out of receiving marketing communications from us. Once these bases have expired, we’ll delete that information.

Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as emails) aren’t secure unless they’ve been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.

The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.

You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including those offered by Google, Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) or using third-party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information.

Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies. You should make sure you’re familiar with these.

Your rights

Below we set out details on how you can exercise your rights. If you have a question or cannot find the answer, please contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com.

Right to correct personal data If you become aware that any of the information we keep about you is incorrect or outdated, you can log into your My Vodafone account to edit your personal details. Alternatively, please contact customer care on 1907.

Right to access personal data If you are a current customer and would like a copy of your personal data, you can submit your request by logging into your My Vodafone account. If you are not an active customer, please send your request to [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) including details of the account in question or any accounts you have previously had.

We will confirm receipt of your request and ensure that you receive this information within one month of the date of your request.

Right to data portability

You can submit a portability request by this by logging into your My Vodafone account.

You will receive your information in a digital, machine-readable format.

Right to object to use of personal data

*   If you do not want your personal information to be used for any purpose, other than those necessary to provide a service to you, please let us know by selecting your data preferences. You can change your preferences at any time using your My Vodafone account. By selecting ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App or by calling 1800 200 234. For customers without a Vodafone mobile number, you can manage your permissions in the V by Vodafone App.

How to lodge a complaint

If you want to contact us about any of your rights, or to enquire or make a complaint about how we use your information, contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com or by email at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) We’ll do our best to help but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact Data Protection Commission. Contact details for the Data Protection Commissioner are:

*   Email: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
    
*   Phone: +353 (0)57 868 4757 or +353 (0)761 104 800
    
*   In writing: Data Protection Office, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, County Laois, R32 AP23, or Data Protection Office, 21 Fitzwilliam Square, Dublin 2, D02 RD28.

Right to restrict use of your data

If you wish to restrict the use of your data by Vodafone, please email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). It is helpful to let us know the reason for your restriction request.

Right to erasure

If you would like us to remove your personal data from our records, you can request this by logging into your My Vodafone account. If you do not have an active account, please email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to let us know what information you would like to have deleted.

We will send you confirmation when your request has been completed. Please note that if you have an active service with us, much of the information that we keep about you cannot be deleted as this is required to provide you with the service to you and to provide support to you.

Our cookie policy

A cookie is a small text file which is placed onto your mobile (or other electronic device) when you access our App. We use cookies on our App to recognise you whenever you visit the App (this speeds up your access to the App as you do not have to log on each time).

Description of cookies

The table below is designed to provide more information about the cookies we use and why:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Name of cookie | Owner | Purpose of the cookie |
| openidAccessToken | Vodafone | These cookies remember who you are to keep you logged into your account on the app so you don’t have to log in every time. |
| openidRefreshToken |     |     |

### V-Auto (product & app)

This privacy statement explains the information that is collected by Vodafone through the V Auto application (‘App’) and as part of delivering connectivity and services via your V-Auto device (‘Connected Device’) and how this data will be processed.

We take the privacy of our users very seriously. We ask that you read this privacy statement carefully as it contains important information about how we will use your personal data.

### Changes to our privacy policy

This Privacy Policy gets updated from time to time; whenever we make a change, we’ll update the content and let you know.  

We have recently revised our Privacy Statement for this App and Service; the main changes are listed below.  

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Section | Changes | Date |
| Reformatted privacy notice | We have updated the structure and format of the privacy notice to meet new legal requirements. | 25thMay 2018 |
| Updated cookie section | Updated with information that is collected via Vodafone ID. | 2ndFebruary 2019 |
| Updated how we collect information and who we share information with | Expanded to include when third party personal data is collected by the user when using the multi-user feature | 6th June 2019 |

Last updated:17/07/2019

Who we are

We are Vodafone Ireland Ltd, a member of the Vodafone Group.

In this privacy policy:

*   “we/us”means \[Vodafone Ireland Ltd.;
    
*   “third party”means someone who is not you or us; and
    
*   “Vodafone Group”means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital.

Our registered office is Vodafone Ireland, Mountain View, Leopardstown, Dublin 18.

We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

Our main switchboard is +353 1 2037000.

V-Auto is powered by our processor, Vodafone Automotive Italia SpA.

How to contact us

Your opinion matters to us –if you have any questions about our privacy policy, you can email us at: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or you can write to our privacy team at:

Data Protection Officer

Vodafone Ireland Mountain View Leopardstown Dublin 18 Ireland

Personal information we collect about you

Information we collect about you

The types of information we process about you when you use your Connected Device and the V-Auto App are:

*   Your name, address, mobile number, date of birth and email address;
    
*   If we need to verify your identity, documentation such as a passport or other identification;
    
*   Your account information, such as the number of products you have with us, dates of payment owed or received and the make, model and year of the vehicle you have;
    
*   Your credential information such as passwords, hints and similar security information used for authentication and access to accounts and services;
    
*   Your preferences for particular products or services when you tell us what they are, or we assume what they are, based on how you use the products and services;
    
*   Customer care information through your contact with us, such as a note or recording of a call you make to one of our contact centres;
    
*   Information about your mobile device each time you use the App. For example, we may collect information on the type of mobile device that you are using and its unique device identifier (for example, the IMEI number, the device’s mobile phone number, or the MAC address of the device’s wireless network interface);
    
*   Information about the V-Sim connectivity, such as the data connections performed and the amount of data consumed, as well as information about the V-Auto device the V-Sim is in;
    
*   Information about your usage of the App, such as how often you use it;
    
*   Your location data. This can be precise where it uses Global Positioning System (GPS) data or by identifying nearby mobile phone masts and Wi-Fi hotspots and you enable location-based services or features. Or less precise where, for example, a location is derived from your IP address or data such as a post code or name of a town or city; and

*   Your driving information such as:

o your trips, so that we can show them to you in the app; and

o your acceleration, braking, driving speed and other driving indicators, so that we can give you feedback on how to make your driving safer and calculate your driving score.

We’ll also get information about how you use our products and services, such as:

*   The level of service that you receive – for example, network or service faults and other events that may affect our network services or other services;
    
*   Details of your use of our services – for example, we can see the amount of data your device is using which we can use to assess whether our data allowances are sufficient; and
    
*   We also collect anonymous analytics information on how our customers use the V-Auto App in order to improve your experience and troubleshoot.

When we collect your personal information

We collect your personal information when:

*   You buy a connected product from us (online, or in store);
    
*   You first register your Connected Device product in the V-Auto App;
    
*   If you’re a non-Vodafone customer, when we verify your identity and you add your payment details;
    
*   You use the V-Auto Application and any of its features (such as Find my Car, Auto SOS, My Trips, and Driver Safety Score);
    
*   You activate and drive with the V-Auto device installed in your vehicle;
    
*   Where a user has nominated you as an additional user to the V-auto product;
    
*   You subscribe to marketing; or
    
*   You contact our customer care teams with a question or complaint.

Third party sources of data

Where necessary, we collect information from certain organisations. These include fraud-prevention agencies, business directories and credit reference agencies.

Where we have partnered with any third parties for promotions or offers you have participated in, we will share aggregate information between us and these parties to measure the success of the initiative.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

1\. The performance of your contract or to enter into the contract and to take action on your requests. For example, we’ll need to process your network traffic data as part of making your V-Auto device “connected” and we’ll need to process your payment details for your monthly billing.

2\. Vodafone’s legitimate business interests, for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, direct marketing, and improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases, you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the Your Rights section of this policy.

3\. Compliance with a mandatory legal obligation, including for example accounting and tax requirements, which are subject to strict internal policies (such as retention periods), procedures, and your right to restrict usage of your data, which control the scope of legal assistance to be provided; or

4\. Consent you provide where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis. Consent is always presented to you separately and you can withdraw your consent at any time.

How we use your personal information

1\. To provide you with your service

We use your information for service provision and to fulfil any purchases you have made:

*   to help us identify you and any accounts you hold with us;
    
*   to provide you with connectivity for your V-Auto device and its functionalities such as Find my Car, Auto SOS, My Trips, and Driver Safety Score;
    
*   billing and customer care;
    
*   to notify you of any changes to the App or to our services that may affect you; and
    
*   identity verification.

2\. Marketing & profiling

If you are opted into marketing and have given us permission to use your data to tailor these communications, we’ll use your interactions with this App and the data from your V-Auto device to inform the sorts of marketing we should be sending you so that it’s the most relevant for you. For example, if we can see that you have purchased V-Pet, we can make sure we don’t market that product to you.

To opt out of Marketing messages or profiling:

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, messaging, phone or post).

There are various ways to opt out:

*   If you are a Vodafone consumer mobile customer, you can log in to your MyVodafone account to manage your marketing permissions and to opt out or into receiving personalised marketing. For customers without a Vodafone mobile number, you can manage your permissions in the V-Auto App.
    
*   Contact our customer care team via v.vodafone.com;
    
*   All our marketing messages come with an “unsubscribe” link which you can click to unsubscribe;
    
*   Tell the adviser if you receive an outbound marketing call;
    
*   Email \[[\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)\] for guidance.

Opting out does not mean that you won’t any longer receive service-related messages, such as messages telling you about your order status or when our Terms & Conditions change. You will still continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise).

3\. Other profiling and automated processing

Outside of the profiling we conduct for marketing purposes to tailor and personalise the communications we send, we use automated processing to generate the insights behind the key functionalities of the App. For example, we:

*   create a driving score for you. This is based on a number of data inputs such as your acceleration, speed and deceleration; and
    
*   provide you contextual information. For example, in the status screen you’ll get offered to set a parking alert if we detect that your car is moving or you’ll get offered directions to your car if we detect from your phone location that you are nearby it.

We also profile you for credit, fraud and security purposes. This can sometimes use systems to make automated decisions based on personal information we have or are allowed to collect from others. The goal is to make the decisions as quick, efficient, fair and correct as possible, based on what we know. It can affect the products or services we may offer you now or in the future.

*   We will carry out a credit check when you apply for a contract for your products and services with us, as described in our privacy [policy](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy).
    
*   If you are not already a Vodafone customer, we will use your personal information for identity verification purposes. We sometimes supplement the information we collect about you with information from other sources (such as the electoral roll) This will be prompted to you on first registration of a connected device within the V by Vodafone or V Auto apps. We also use this verification for access to your account and for general account management. However, this identity verification process is supported by human agents that will verify the output of the automated decision.
    
*   We will process your personal data in order to protect against and detect fraud, and to recover debts or trace those who owe us money resulting from the use of our services.

4\. Service improvement

*   We collect anonymous, de-identified or aggregate information in order to improve the service we offer to everyone. None of these analytics are linked back to you in any way.
    
*   To protect our networks and manage the volumes of calls, texts and other uses of our networks. For example, we identify peak periods of use so we can try and ensure the networks can handle the volume at those times; and
    
*   To understand how you use our networks, products and services. That way we can seek to review, develop and improve these, develop more interesting and relevant products and services, as well as personalising our products and services.

How we share your personal information

Some features of your V-Auto device require us to share information with third parties, but we’ll ask you before we do, as these are optional. For example, when our agents ring you when Auto SOS has detected a collision, we ask you whether you need us to send help to the car’s location. Additionally, when we partner with third parties that can offer you services based on data such as your location, your driving score, or whether you’ve been in an accident we make sure no data is shared unless you actively request us to do so.

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group;
    
*   Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used;
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Limited, or Vodafone Group;
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Third parties who you have nominated to view your driver information via the app;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law; or
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.

International data transfers

If you are a non-Vodafone customer and we need to verify your identity, we will need to transfer your data to our service provider, which is based in India.

When Vodafone sends your information to a country that is not in the EEA, we make sure that your information is properly protected. We will always ensure that there is a proper legal agreement that covers the data transfer. In addition, if the country is not considered to have laws that are equivalent to EU data protection standards then we will ask the third party to enter into a legal agreement that reflects those standards.

How long we keep your personal information for

We’ll store and process your information for as long as we have to by law or as long as we need to be able to deliver you the services you have requested. We’ll keep some personal information for a reasonable period after your contract with us has finished in case you decide to use our services again. We, or one of our partners, may contact you about Vodafone services during this time if you haven’t opted out of receiving marketing communications from us. Once these bases have expired, we’ll delete that information.

Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as emails) aren’t secure unless they’ve been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.

The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.

You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including those offered by Google, Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) or using third-party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information.

Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies. You should make sure you’re familiar with these.

Your rights

Below we set out details on how you can exercise your rights. If you have a question or cannot find the answer, please contact our customer care team via. v.vodafone.com/ie

Right to correct personal data

If you become aware that any of the information we keep about you is incorrect or outdated, you can log into your My Vodafone account to edit your personal details. Alternatively, please contact customer care on 1907.

Right to access personal data If you are a current customer and would like a copy of your personal data, you can submit your request by logging into your My Vodafone account. If you are not an active customer, please send your request to [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) including details of the account in question or any accounts you have previously had.

We will confirm receipt of your request and ensure that you receive this information within one month of the date of your request.

Right to data portability You can submit a portability request by this by logging into your My Vodafone account. You will receive your information in a digital, machine-readable format.

Right to object to use of personal data · If you do not want your personal information to be used for any purpose, other than those necessary to provide a service to you, please let us know by selecting your data preferences. You can change your preferences at any time using your My Vodafone account, by selecting ‘settings’ on the My Vodafone App or by calling 1800 200 234. For customers without a Vodafone mobile number, you can manage your permissions in the V by Vodafone App.

How to lodge a complaint If you want to contact us about any of your rights, or to enquire or make a complaint about how we use your information, contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com or by email at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) We’ll do our best to help but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact Data Protection Commission. Contact details for the Data Protection Commissioner are:

*   Email: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
    
*   Phone: +353 (0)57 868 4757 or +353 (0)761 104 800
    
*   In writing: Data Protection Office, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, County Laois, R32 AP23, or Data Protection Office, 21 Fitzwilliam Square, Dublin 2, D02 RD28.

Right to restrict use of your data

If you wish to restrict the use of your data by Vodafone, please email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). It is helpful to let us know the reason for your restriction request.

Our cookie policy

How we use cookies

A cookie is a small text file which is placed onto your mobile (or other electronic device) when you access our App. We use cookies on our App to recognise you whenever you visit the App (this speeds up your access to the App as you do not have to log on each time).

Our cookies don't hold personal information such as your name or bank details. They simply let us find information about your browsing experience that we can associate to you if you are logged in.

To do this we sometimes use persistent cookies. We take looking after your personal information seriously – we're always monitoring and improving how we protect it.

We've put our cookies into the following categories, to make it easier for you to understand why we need them:

1\. Strictly necessary – these are used to help make our website work efficiently

2\. Performance – these are used to analyse the way our website works and how we can improve it

3\. Functionality – these help to enhance your experience by doing things like remembering products you've added to your basket

4\. Targeting/advertising – these are used to share some information with third parties who we advertise with, so we know how you've reached our website. We can also use cookies to identify the parts of the website you’re interested in. We then use this information to show you adverts and pages we think may also be of interest to you, to tailor how we communicate with you, or to tailor the contents of the communications we send to you. If you prefer, you can opt out of these. Tailoring of content means it includes information reflecting the interest you’ve shown in the content of our web pages, or offers or promotions that we think may interest you, and to improve how we respond to your needs.

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| What’s its called | What it is used for | Type | Duration |
| VF-UUID | This allows us to track browser actions to understand how Vodafone ID is being used (e.g. button clicks, page load times etc.) | 2   | Persistent cookie |
| Session | To track your web session. After successful authentication this cookie is set to keep the authenticated session (and authorisation details) active in the browser. This means if you come back in the same browser within 30 minutes, you do not need to re-authenticate. | 1   | 30 minutes |
| loadedData<br><br>loadedData1<br><br>marketChange | When you select what country you are in, these cookies remember your selection. | 3   | On browser close |
| Trx | To track time out for current transaction | 1   | 10 minutes |
| Auth\_${AuthorizationId} | To track time out for transaction | 1   | 1 Day |
| Language | To track language selection | 2   | 30 Days |
| Recall | To track “remember me” settings | 2   | On browser close |
| sessionTimerData | To track transaction time out | 2   | Session |
| origin\_tealium\_profile | Functional Cookie used to derive the profile (i.e. UK) used by Tealium and hand this over to the Service (e.g. V Shop) | 3   | Session |
| origin\_tealium\_environment | This is a functional cookie used to identify the environment (web environment not location i.e. live web page or testing web page) used by the customer and hand this over to the Service (e.g. V Shop) to locate traffic | 3   | 1 year |
| utag\_main | This is a tracking/behavioural cookie that contains different information about the session and presents a unique identifier of the customer in that session.<br><br>This gathers usage statistics used to analyse customer behaviour/ trends taking place on our site and use it to improve customer experience and performance of our site to give you the best experience possible.<br><br>All variable listed here:<br><br>ses\_id<br><br>– A unique identifier for the session.<br><br>\_st<br><br>– A Unix/Epoch time stamp, in milliseconds.<br><br>v\_id<br><br>– A unique identifier for each visitor.<br><br>\_ss<br><br>– A Boolean that indicates if the page viewed is the first in a session. A value of 1 means yes and 0 means no.<br><br>\_pn<br><br>– The number of pages viewed during the current session.<br><br>\_sn<br><br>– The number of sessions for this visitor. | 3   |     |
| openidAccessToken<br><br>openidRefreshToken | These cookies remember who you are to keep you logged into your account on the app so you don’t have to log in every time. | 1   | Session |

Controlling your cookies

You can control how you use cookies in your browser or your device settings.

If you change your cookie settings in your browser, your experience with us won't be tracked.

Information on controlling and deleting cookies is also available at [http://allaboutcookies.org](http://allaboutcookies.org/)

### Curve

### Curve - Smart Tracker – VST001– Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement explains how we process the information of:

*   subscribers whose data may be collected through the V by Vodafone app (‘App’); and
    
*   users whose data may be collected via the Smart Tracker with model ID VST001 (‘Device’).

We take the privacy of our subscribers and users very seriously. We ask that you read this Privacy Statement carefully as it contains important information about how we will use your personal data.

If you are sharing your device with others, as the main account owner you are responsible for ensuring that such users have been made aware of the personal data processing, including location data, as outlined in this statement.

This Privacy Policy gets updated from time to time; whenever we make a change, we’ll update the content and let you know.

We have recently revised our Privacy Statement for this App and Service; the main changes are listed below.

Last updated: 19/07/2021

### Who we are

We are Vodafone Ireland Limited, a member of the Vodafone Group.

In this privacy policy:

*   “we/us” means Vodafone Ireland Limited;
    
*   “third party” means someone who is not you or us; and
    
*   “Vodafone Group” means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital.

Vodafone Ireland limited is a private Company Limited by Shares, registered in Ireland with registered office at MountainView, Leopardstown, Dublin18. We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

Our main switchboard is 1907 or you can email us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) .

### How to contact us

Your opinion matters to us – if you have any questions about our privacy policy, you can email us at: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) com or you can write to our privacy team at:

Vodafone Privacy Team

Vodafone Ireland Limited  
MountainView

Leopardstown,

Dublin 18

D18 XN97

Ireland

### Personal information we collect about you

Information we collect about you

The types of information we process includes;

*   Your name, address, mobile number or landline number, date of birth and email address;
    
*   Your account information, such as the number of products you have with us, dates of payment owed or received and the make, model and year of the vehicle you have;
    
*   Your photos or camera settings, if you want to add photos for profile setup, including the user of the device, to their respective profiles (you can revoke these permissions in your phone’s Settings);
    
*   Your credential information such as passwords, hints and similar security information used for authentication and access to accounts and services;
    
*   Your preferences for particular products or services when you tell us what they are, or we assume what they are, based on how you use the products and services;
    
*   Customer care information through your contact with us, such as a note or recording of a call you make to one of our contact centres;
    
*   Information about your mobile handset each time you use the App. For example, we may collect information on the type of mobile device that you are using and its unique device identifier (for example, the IMEI number, the device’s mobile phone number, or the MAC address of the device’s wireless network interface);
    
*   Information about your usage of the App, such as how often you use it or when you dismiss alerts; and
    
*   Your mobile handset or device location data. This can be precise where it uses Global Positioning System (GPS) data or by identifying nearby mobile phone masts and Wi-Fi hotspots and you enable location-based services or features. The device will always process location data in order for you to locate the device however, you can turn of location tracking of your mobile handset at any time.
    
*   Information about your interaction with the App and its features, such as voice related activity if you choose to connect your device with another third party device (for example Alexa). If you do, the other device provider will share with us your “voice intents” which includes the content of your requests to enable us to provide and improve your experience and our services (you can stop the sharing of this information with us by unlinking the devices/removing our access to the other device).

We’ll also get information about how you use our products and services, such as:

*   The level of service that you receive – for example, network or service faults and other events that may affect our network services or other services;
    
*   Details of your use of our services – for example, we can see the amount of data the device is using which we can use to assess whether our data allowances are sufficient; and
    
*   We also collect anonymous analytics information on how users use the device and app in order to improve your experience and troubleshoot.

When we collect your personal information

We collect personal information when:

*   You first set up your device in the App and set up your profile;
    
*   You use the App and any of its features (for example, setting a geographical zone or changing tracking mode);
    
*   You subscribe to marketing; or
    
*   You contact our customer care teams.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

1\. The performance of your contract or to enter into the contract and to take action on your requests. For example, we’ll need to process your network traffic data as part of making your device “connected” and we’ll need to process subscriber’s payment details for your monthly billing.

2\. Vodafone’s legitimate business interests, for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, direct marketing, and improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the Your Rights section of this policy.

3\. Compliance with a mandatory legal obligation, including for example accounting and tax requirements, which are subject to strict internal policies (such as retention periods), procedures, and your right to restrict usage of your data, which control the scope of legal assistance to be provided; or

4\. Consent you provide where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis. Consent is always presented to you separately and you can withdraw your consent at any time.

### How we use your personal information

1\. To provide you with your service

We use your information for service provision and to fulfil any purchases you have made:

*   to help us identify you and any accounts you hold with us;
    
*   to provide you with connectivity and features for your device;
    
*   billing and customer care;
    
*   to notify you of any changes to the App or to our services that may affect you; and
    
*   identity verification.

2\. Marketing and profiling

If your Vodafone account is opted into marketing and you have given us permission to use your data to tailor these communications, we’ll use your interactions with this App and the data from your Connected Device to inform the sorts of marketing we should be sending you so that it’s the most relevant for you. For example, we can see whether you are getting the most out of your purchase or which Products you already have.

To opt out of Marketing messages or profiling:

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, messaging, phone or post).  

There are various ways to opt out:  

*   Contact our customer care team on 1907
    
*   Log onto My Vodafone though the Vodafone website or via My Vodafone app to review and change your marketing preferences
    
*   Tell the adviser you no longer want to be marketed to, if you receive an outbound marketing call;
    
*   Email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for guidance.
    
*   Opting out does not mean that you won’t any longer receive service-related messages, such as messages telling you about your order status or when our Terms and Conditions change. You will still continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise). You may also receive marketing via push notifications if you have not turned them off via your App settings.

3\. Service improvement

We collect anonymous, de-identified or aggregated information in order to improve the service we offer to everyone.  

To protect our networks and manage the volumes of calls, texts and other uses of our networks. For example, we identify peak periods of use so we can try and ensure the networks can handle the volume at those times; and

To understand how you use our networks, products and services. That way we can seek to review, develop and improve these, develop more interesting and relevant products and services, as well as personalising our products and services.

We also process call recordings or chat transcripts when you interact with our customer care, for training and quality purposes.

### How we share your personal information

Where applicable, we share information about you with:  

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group;
    
*   Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used (for example our supplier Trackimo who help to build the product);
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Limited, or Vodafone Group;
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law; or
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.

### International data transfers

Our customer care centres are run by Vodafone Shared Services which is based in Egypt and India.  

The data accessed will only include support ticket data needed to resolve your issues. For example, your phone number or fall detection data is not transferred.  

If you are a non-Vodafone customer and we need to verify your identity, we will need to transfer your data to our service provider, which is based in India.  

When Vodafone sends your information to a country that is not in the EEA, we make sure that your information is properly protected. We will always ensure that there is a proper legal agreement that covers the data transfer. In addition, if the country is not considered to have laws that are equivalent to EU data protection standards then we will ask the third party to enter into a legal agreement that reflects those standards.  

### How long we keep your personal information for

We’ll store and process your information for as long as we have to by law or as long as we need to be able to deliver you the services you have requested. We’ll keep some personal information for a reasonable period after your contract with us has finished in case you decide to use our services again. We, or one of our partners, may contact you about Vodafone services during this time if you haven’t opted out of receiving marketing communications from us. Once these bases have expired, we’ll delete that information.  

### Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.  

Communications over the internet (such as emails) aren’t secure unless they’ve been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.  

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.  

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.  

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.  

The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.  

You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including those offered by Google, Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) or using third-party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information.  

Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies. You should make sure you’re familiar with these.  

### Your rights

Below we set out details on how you can exercise your rights. If you have a question or cannot find the answer, please contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com.  

Right to correct personal data

You have the right to have your personal data corrected if it is incorrect. You can request this by contacting our Customer Services team online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Right to access personal data

You have the right to make a request for a copy of the personal data that Vodafone holds about you. To make this request as an individual or an authorised 3rd party, please contact the Customer Services online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Right to data portability

You have the right to port your data. You can request this by contacting our Customer Services Team online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Right to object to use of personal data

In certain circumstances, you have the right to object to the use of your personal data. Contact our Customer Services team online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

How to lodge a complaint

If you want to contact us about any of your rights or if complain about how we use your information, contact our Customer Services team online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We’ll do our best to help but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact by post to the Data Protection Commission, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, R32 AP23 Co Laois.”

Right to restrict use of your data

If you feel data we hold on you is inaccurate or believe we shouldn’t be processing your data, please contact our Customer Services team online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to discuss your rights. In certain circumstances you will have the right to ask us to restrict processing.  

Right to erasure

Vodafone strives to only process and retain your data for as long as we need to. In certain circumstances you have the right to request that we erase personal data of yours that we hold. If you feel that we are retaining your data longer than we need, it is worth first checking that your contract with Vodafone has been terminated which you can do with our Customer Services team online or by calling 1907. If your contract with Vodafone has been terminated, we may still have lawful grounds to process your personal data. For more information on retention periods please see [Privacy policy](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy).

### Neo - The smart kids watch

Smart Childrens Watch (VKW001) – Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement explains how we process the information:

*   of Administrators whose data may be collected through the Vodafone Smart app (‘App’); and
    
*   wearer’s (‘User’s’), collected via the connected device (‘Connected Device’).

We take the privacy of our users very seriously. We ask that you read this Privacy Statement carefully as it contains important information about how we will use your personal data.

Last updated: 14/07/2021

This Privacy Policy gets updated from time to time; whenever we make a change, we’ll update the content and let you know.

We have recently revised our Privacy Statement for this App and Service; the main changes are listed below.

Last updated: \[03 August 2021\]

Who we are

We are Vodafone Ireland Limited, a member of the Vodafone Group.

In this privacy policy:

*   “we/us” means Vodafone Ireland Limited;
    
*   “you/your” means the user of the account owner or the user of the Connected Device
    
*   “third party” means someone who is not you or us; and
    
*   “Vodafone Group” means Vodafone Group Plc and any company or other organisation in which Vodafone Group Plc owns more than 15% of the share capital.

Vodafone Ireland limited is a private Company Limited by Shares, registered in Ireland with registered office at MountainView, Leopardstown, Dublin18. We are registered in Ireland under company number 326967.

Our main switchboard is 1907 or you can email us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) .

How to contact us

Your opinion matters to us – if you have any questions about our privacy policy, you can email us at: [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or you can write to our privacy team at:

Vodafone Privacy Team

Vodafone Ireland Limited MountainView

Leopardstown,

Dublin 18

D18 XN97

Ireland

Personal information we collect about you

Information we collect about you

The types of information we process includes;

*   Your name, address, mobile number or landline number, date of birth and email address;
    
*   Your account information, such as the number of products you have with us, dates of payment owed or received and the type of Connected Device you have;
    
*   Your phone’s address book, so that you can add contacts to the group (you can revoke these permissions in your phone’s Settings);
    
*   Your photos or camera settings, if you want to add photos of Group members, including the User of the device, to their respective profiles (you can revoke these permissions in your phone’s Settings);
    
*   Your preferences for particular products or services when you tell us what they are, or we assume what they are, based on how you use the products and services;
    
*   Customer care information through your contact with us, such as a note or recording of a call you make to one of our contact centres;
    
*   Information about your Connected Device each time you use the App. For example, we may collect information on the type of device that you are using and its unique device identifier (for example, the IMEI number, the device’s mobile phone number, or the MAC address of the device’s wireless network interface);
    
*   Messages between your phone and the device, this is stored locally on your devices;
    
*   Information about your usage of the App, such as how often you use it or when you dismiss alerts; and
    
*   Your Connected Device location data. This can be precise where it uses Global Positioning System (GPS) data or by identifying nearby mobile phone masts and Wi-Fi hotspots and you enable location-based services or features. Or less precise where, for example, a location is derived from your IP address or data such as a post code or name of a town or city.
    
*   We’ll also get information about how you use our products and services, such as:
    
*   The level of service that you receive – for example, network or service faults and other events that may affect our network services or other services;
    
*   Details of your use of our services – for example, we can see the amount of data the Connected Device is using which we can use to assess whether our data allowances are sufficient; and
    
*   We also collect anonymous analytics information on how users use the Connected Device in order to improve your experience and troubleshoot.

When we collect your personal information

We collect personal information when:

*   You first set up your Connected Device product in the App and add your contact details and those of contacts;
    
*   You use the App and any of its features (for example, dismissing alerts or messaging other contacts);
    
*   You subscribe to marketing; or
    
*   You contact our customer care teams with a query.

Vodafone will process your personal data based on:

1\. The performance of your contract or to enter into the contract and to take action on your requests. For example, we’ll need to process your network traffic data as part of making your device “connected” and we’ll need to process Administrator's payment details for your monthly billing.

2\. Vodafone’s legitimate business interests, for example, fraud prevention, maintaining the security of our network and services, direct marketing, and improvement of our services. Whenever we rely on this lawful basis to process your data, we assess our business interests to make sure they do not override your rights. Additionally, in some cases you have the right to object to this processing. For more information, visit the Your Rights section of this policy.

3\. Compliance with a mandatory legal obligation, including for example accounting and tax requirements, which are subject to strict internal policies (such as retention periods), procedures, and your right to restrict usage of your data, which control the scope of legal assistance to be provided; or

4\. Consent you provide where Vodafone does not rely on another legal basis. Consent is always presented to you separately and you can withdraw your consent at any time.

How we use your personal information

1\. To provide you with your service

We use your information for service provision and to fulfil any purchases you have made:

*   to help us identify you and any accounts you hold with us;
    
*   to provide you with connectivity for your Connected Device;
    
*   billing and customer care;
    
*   to notify you of any changes to the App or to our services that may affect you; and
    
*   identity verification.

1\. Marketing and profiling

If your Vodafone account is opted into marketing and you have given us permission to use your data to tailor these communications, we’ll use your interactions with this App and the data from your Connected Device to inform the sorts of marketing we should be sending you so that it’s the most relevant for you. For example, we can see whether you are getting the most out of your purchase or which Products you already have.

To opt out of Marketing messages or profiling:

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from Vodafone, you can elect to opt out of all marketing communications or only selected methods (email, messaging, phone or post).

There are various ways to opt out:

*   Contact our customer care team on 1907
    
*   Log onto My Vodafone though the Vodafone website or via My Vodafone app to review and change your marketing preferences
    
*   Tell the adviser you no longer want to be marketed to, if you receive an outbound marketing call;
    
*   Email [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for guidance.
    
*   Opting out does not mean that you won’t any longer receive service-related messages, such as messages telling you about your order status or when our Terms and Conditions change. You will still continue to receive those (unless we have indicated otherwise). You may also receive marketing via push notifications if you have not turned them off via your App settings.

2\. Service improvement

We collect anonymous, de-identified or aggregate information in order to improve the service we offer to everyone. None of these analytics are linked back to you in any way.

To protect our networks and manage the volumes of calls, texts and other uses of our networks. For example, we identify peak periods of use so we can try and ensure the networks can handle the volume at those times; and

To understand how you use our networks, products and services. That way we can seek to review, develop and improve these, develop more interesting and relevant products and services, as well as personalising our products and services.

How we share your personal information

Where applicable, we share information about you with:

*   Companies in the Vodafone Group;
    
*   Partners, suppliers or agents involved in delivering the products and services you’ve ordered or used;
    
*   Companies who are engaged to perform services for, or on behalf of, Vodafone Limited, or Vodafone Group;
    
*   Credit reference, fraud-prevention or business-scoring agencies, or other credit scoring agencies;
    
*   Debt collection agencies or other debt-recovery organisations;
    
*   Law enforcement agencies, government bodies, regulatory organisations, courts or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law; or
    
*   A third party or body where such disclosure is required to satisfy any applicable law, or other legal or regulatory requirement.
    
*   Smartcomm for neo \[MHV1\]

International data transfers

Our customer care centres are run by Vodafone Shared Services which is based in Hungary, Egypt, India and Romania.

Our processor [Smartcomm](https://www.smartcommunications.com/external-privacy-policy/), who provide the platform and will access the data in case there are any troubleshooting queries, will store your data in the EEA

The data accessed will only include support ticket data needed to resolve your issues. For example, your phone number or issues with the device.

If you are a non-Vodafone customer and we need to verify your identity, we will need to transfer your data to our service provider, which is based in India.

When Vodafone sends your information to a country that is not in the EEA, we make sure that your information is properly protected. We will always ensure that there is a proper legal agreement that covers the data transfer. In addition, if the country is not considered to have laws that are equivalent to EU data protection standards then we will ask the third party to enter into a legal agreement that reflects those standards.

How long we keep your personal information for

We’ll store and process your information for as long as we have to by law or as long as we need to be able to deliver you the services you have requested. We’ll keep some personal information for a reasonable period after your contract with us has finished in case you decide to use our services again. We, or one of our partners, may contact you about Vodafone services during this time if you haven’t opted out of receiving marketing communications from us. Once these bases have expired, we’ll delete that information.

Keeping your personal information secure

We have specialised security teams who constantly review and improve our measures to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, accidental loss, disclosure or destruction.

Communications over the internet (such as emails) aren’t secure unless they’ve been encrypted. Your communications may go through a number of countries before being delivered, as this is the nature of the internet.

We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We’ll never ask for your secure personal or account information by an unsolicited means of communication. You’re responsible for keeping your personal and account information secure and not sharing it with others.

Our website may provide links to third-party websites. We cannot be responsible for the security and content of such third-party websites. So make sure you read that company’s privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your personal information on their site.

The same applies to any third-party websites or content you connect to using our products and services.

You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including those offered by Google, Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) or using third-party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information.

Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies. You should make sure you’re familiar with these.

Your rights

Below we set out details on how you can exercise your rights. If you have a question or cannot find the answer, please contact our Customer Services team via v.vodafone.com.

Right to correct personal data

You have the right to have your personal data corrected if it is incorrect. You can request this by contacting our Customer Services team online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Right to access personal data

You have the right to make a request for a copy of the personal data that Vodafone holds about you. To make this request as an individual or an authorised 3rd party, please contact the Customer Services online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Right to data portability

You have the right to port your data. You can request this by contacting our Customer Services Team online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Right to object to use of personal data

In certain circumstances, you have the right to object to the use of your personal data. Contact our Customer Services team online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

How to lodge a complaint

If you want to contact us about any of your rights or if complain about how we use your information, contact our Customer Services team online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We’ll do our best to help but if you’re still unhappy, you can contact Data Protection Commission - by post to Data Protection Commission, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, R32 AP23 Co Laois.

Right to restrict use of your data

If you feel data we hold on you is inaccurate or believe we shouldn’t be processing your data, please contact our Customer Services team online or by calling 1907 or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to discuss your rights. In certain circumstances you will have the right to ask us to restrict processing.

Right to erasure

Vodafone strives to only process and retain your data for as long as we need to. In certain circumstances you have the right to request that we erase personal data of yours that we hold. If you feel that we are retaining your data longer than we need, it is worth first checking that your contract with Vodafone has been terminated which you can do with our Customer Services team online or by calling 1907. If your contract with Vodafone has been terminated, we may still have lawful grounds to process your personal data. For more information on retention periods please see [privacy](https://n.vodafone.ie/privacy)

\[MHV1\]This is covered in 2nd bullet point (our partners, suppliers or agents etc.)

Our cookie policy
-----------------

Check our cookie policy as cookies on your device can improve your online experience and give you personalised and tailored offers.

### What are cookies?

Cookies are tiny text files that are stored on your computer, tablet or mobile phone when you visit a website. They mean that the website will remember you and how you've used the site every time you come back.

If you want to know more about cookies, head to [aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [allaboutcookies.org](https://allaboutcookies.org/).

We only use cookies based on your consent (except for strictly necessary cookies) and you can manage how we use cookies through the Cookie Settings mentioned in dropdowns below.

### How we use cookies

We use cookies to do a number of things. For example, remembering your preferences, recording what you’ve put in your shopping basket, or counting the number of people looking at the website. We also use cookies to keep track of what you've bought from us and what you've done on the site and to understand how you came to our site. Cookies also mean you can use services such as tracking your order, checking your account or topping up.Our cookies don't hold personal information such as your name or bank details - they simply let us find that information once you're logged in. We take looking after your details seriously – we're always monitoring and improving how we protect your personal information.

### Cookie List

A cookie is a small piece of data (text file) that a website – when visited by a user – asks your browser to store on your device in order to remember information about you, such as your language preference or login information. Those cookies are set by us and called first-party cookies. We also use third-party cookies – which are cookies from a domain different than the domain of the website you are visiting – for our advertising and marketing efforts. More specifically, we use cookies and other tracking technologies for the following purposes:

#### Strictly Necessary Cookies

These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms. You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but some parts of the site will not then work. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information.

| Cookie Subgroup | Cookies | Cookies used | Lifespan |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| n.vodafone.ie | [AWSALB](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/AWSALB) , [OAMAuthnCookie\_n.vodafone.ie:443](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/OAMAuthnCookie_n.vodafone.ie:443) , [AWSALBCORS](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/AWSALBCORS) , [SHIROCOOKIE](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/SHIROCOOKIE) | First Party | 6 Days, Session, 6 Days, Session |
| .vodafone.ie | [visid\_incap\_xxxxxxx](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/visid_incap_xxxxxxx) , [OptanonConsent](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/OptanonConsent) , [nlbi\_XXXXXXX](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/nlbi_XXXXXXX) , [incap\_ses\_xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/incap_ses_xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx) , [CONSENTMGR](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/CONSENTMGR) , [utag\_main](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/utag_main) , [OptanonAlertBoxClosed](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/OptanonAlertBoxClosed) | First Party | 364 Days, 364 Days, 364 Days, 364 Days, 364 Days, 364 Days, 364 Days |
| [.tealiumiq.com](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.tealiumiq.com) | TAPID | Third Party | 364 Days |

#### Performance Cookies

Performance cookies collect information about how visitors use our website, such as which pages are visited most often and if users encounter error messages. These cookies also collect specific data to help us understand usage patterns. We combine this data with account information to provide a more personalized and improved services. While these cookies help us enhance website performance and user experience, they collect personal information that can be linked to individual accounts or user profiles. If you do not allow these cookies we will not know when you have visited our site, collect information and will not be able to monitor its performance.

| Cookie Subgroup | Cookies | Cookies used | Lifespan |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| n.vodafone.ie | [LID](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/LID) , [smapi\_subject\_id](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/smapi_subject_id) , [ADRUM\_xxxx](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/ADRUM_xxxx) | First Party | 395 Days, 364 Days, A few seconds |
| deviceguides.vodafone.ie | [smapi\_install\_id](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/smapi_install_id) | First Party | 364 Days |
| .vodafone.ie | [da\_lid](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/da_lid) , [\_ga\_xxxxxxxxxx](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/_ga_xxxxxxxxxx) , [s\_sq](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/s_sq) , [s\_fid](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/s_fid) , [\_uetvid](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/_uetvid) , [s\_cc](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/s_cc) , [\_ga](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/_ga) , [\_gid](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/_gid) , [s\_dfa](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/s_dfa) , [da\_intState](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/da_intState) | First Party | 364 Days, 399 Days, 364 Days, 399 Days, 389 Days, 364 Days, 399 Days, A few seconds, A few seconds, A few seconds |
| vodafone.ie | [s\_ecid](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/s_ecid) | First Party | 399 Days |
| [.jivox.com](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.jivox.com) | jvxsync | Third Party | 89 Days |
| [.decibelinsight.net](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.decibelinsight.net) | da\_lid | Third Party | 364 Days |
| [.quantserve.com](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.quantserve.com) | d   | Third Party | 89 Days |

#### Functional Cookies

These cookies enable the website to provide enhanced functionality and personalisation. They may be set by us or by third party providers whose services we have added to our pages. If you do not allow these cookies then some or all of these services may not function properly.

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Cookie Subgroup | Cookies | Cookies used | Lifespan |
| vodafone.ie | [utag\_main 2](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/utag_main%202) | First Party | 365 Days |
| .n.vodafone.ie | [\_pin\_unauth](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/_pin_unauth) | First Party | 364 Days |
| .vodafone.ie | [at\_check](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/at_check) ,[mbox](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/mbox) ,[da\_sid](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/da_sid) ,[OAMAuthnHintCookie](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/OAMAuthnHintCookie) | First Party | 364 Days, 399 Days, A few seconds, 364 Days |
| deviceguides.vodafone.ie | [kampyleSessionPageCounter](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/kampyleSessionPageCounter) ,[\_\_\_utmvxxxxxxxxxxxxxx](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/___utmvxxxxxxxxxxxxxx) ,[kampyleUserSessionsCount](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/kampyleUserSessionsCount) ,[mdLogger](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/mdLogger) ,[kampyle\_userid](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/kampyle_userid) | First Party | 364 Days, A few seconds, 364 Days, 364 Days, 364 Days |
| n.vodafone.ie | [basketIdentifier](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/basketIdentifier) ,[kampyleUserSession](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/kampyleUserSession) ,[changeProductInBasket](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/changeProductInBasket) | First Party | 729 Days, 364 Days, A few seconds |

#### Targeting Cookies

These cookies may be set through our site by our advertising partners. They may be used by those companies to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant adverts on other sites. They do not store directly personal information, but are based on uniquely identifying your browser and internet device. If you do not allow these cookies, you will experience less targeted advertising.

*   ##### Social Media Cookies
    
    These cookies are set by a range of social media services that we have added to the site to enable you to share our content with your friends and networks. They are capable of tracking your browser across other sites and building up a profile of your interests. This may impact the content and messages you see on other websites you visit. If you do not allow these cookies you may not be able to use or see these sharing tools.

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Cookie Subgroup | Cookies | Cookies used | Lifespan |
| deviceguides.vodafone.ie | [adformfrpid](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/adformfrpid) | First Party | 29 Days |
| vodafone.ie | [ipconsent](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/ipconsent) ,[utag\_main 3](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/utag_main%203) | First Party | 2 Years, 365 Days |
| .vodafone.ie | [\_gat\_xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/_gat_xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx) ,[\_fbp](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/_fbp) ,[AMCVS\_xxxxxAdobeOrg](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/AMCVS_xxxxxAdobeOrg) ,[\_gcl\_au](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/_gcl_au) ,[\_dlt](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/_dlt) ,[AMCV\_xxxxxAdobeOrg](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/AMCV_xxxxxAdobeOrg) ,[\_uetsid](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/_uetsid) ,[\_\_qca](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/cookies/__qca) | First Party | A few seconds, 89 Days, 364 Days, 89 Days, A few seconds, 399 Days, A few seconds, 391 Days |
| [.everesttech.net](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.everesttech.net) | everest\_g\_v2, everest\_session\_v2 | Third Party | 680 Days, Session |
| [adform.net](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/adform.net) | C, CM, uid, CM14 | Third Party | 29 Days, A few seconds, 59 Days, A few seconds |
| [ct.pinterest.com](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/ct.pinterest.com) | \_pinterest\_ct\_ua | Third Party | 364 Days |
| [doubleclick.net](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/doubleclick.net) | receive-cookie-deprecation | Third Party | 179 Days |
| [seadform.net](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/seadform.net) | uid | Third Party | 60 Days |
| [.decibelinsight.net](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.decibelinsight.net) | intState, da\_sid | Third Party | A few seconds, A few seconds |
| [.dpm.demdex.net](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.dpm.demdex.net) | dpm | Third Party | 130 Days |
| [.google.com](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.google.com) | \_\_Secure-xxxxxxx, SSID, SAPISID | Third Party | 266 Days, 266 Days, 266 Days |
| [.doubleclick.net](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.doubleclick.net) | receive-cookie-deprecation, test\_cookie, IDE | Third Party | 179 Days, A few seconds, 298 Days |
| [.adform.net](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.adform.net) | uid, CM, CM14, C | Third Party | 59 Days, A few seconds, A few seconds, 30 Days |
| [.demdex.net](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.demdex.net) | dextp, demdex | Third Party | 179 Days, 130 Days |
| [.quantserve.com](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.quantserve.com) | mc  | Third Party | 395 Days |
| [.pinterest.com](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.pinterest.com) | ar\_debug | Third Party | 364 Days |
| [.ct.pinterest.com](https://cookiepedia.co.uk/host/.ct.pinterest.com) | \_pinterest\_ct\_ua | Third Party | 364 Days |

### Cookies and you

To buy a phone or sign up to services like My Vodafone or Vodafone Cherry Points on Pay as you go, you must have cookies enabled on your internet browser. The more popular ones are:

*   Internet Explorer
    
*   Firefox
    
*   Safari
    
*   Google Chrome

You can still see the website if you choose not to enable cookies. If cookies aren't enabled, your shopping experience will be limited to just browsing our site.

### Controlling your cookies

You can control Vodafone website cookies by clicking the Cookie Settings button. You can control how you use cookies on all websites through your browser settings. If you don't know what browser you're using, find out by:  

*   PC users: Go to 'Help' in your browser and choosing 'About'.
    
*   Mac users: Click on the Apple menu and choose 'About'.

### How to enable cookies for PCs

#### Google Chrome

1.  Go to Settings
    
2.  Near the bottom of the page, select Show advanced settings.
    
3.  In the "Privacy" section, select Content settings.
    
4.  Select Allow local data to be set (recommended).
    
5.  Select Done.

#### Microsoft Internet Explorer 9.0

1.  Click the Tools button and then click Internet options.
    
2.  Click the Privacy tab, and then, under Settings, move the slider to the top to block all cookies or to the bottom to allow all cookies, and then click OK

#### Mozilla Firefox

1.  Click the menu button at the top right of your browser window and select Options.
    
2.  Then select the Privacy icon.
    
3.  Set 'Firefox will:'' to 'Use custom settings for history'.
    
4.  Check mark Accept cookies from sites to enable Cookies, and uncheck it to disable them.

#### Safari on OSX

1.  Choose Safari
    
2.  Select Preferences followed by Privacy.
    
3.  You can then choose to block or unblock cookies.

### Block cookies

If you'd like to find out how to stop websites using cookies to remember what sites you visit, choose your browser from the list. This will take you to the browser's respective page where you can manage your cookies and site data:

### Local Storage

What is Local Storage

Local Storage is a type of web storage that allows JavaScript sites and apps to store and access data right in the browser with no expiration date. This means the data stored in the browser will persist even after the browser window has been closed.

How We Use Local Storage

We use local storage to keep track of which of our digital tools you have used and what you've done on the site. Local Storage also means you can use additional services such as live chat or allows us to survey customers regarding their experience. Some examples of local storage values are below.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Host | Key | Value |
| https://www.vodafone.ie | bc.visitor\_token | {"token":"6696527780874059776"} |
| https://www.vodafone.ie | kampyle\_userid | 6ac0-2b32-f63f-944e-1369-8345-78c6-8113 |
| https://www.vodafone.ie | kampyleSessionPageCounter | 1   |
| https://www.vodafone.ie | kampyleUserSession | 1601735800079 |
| https://www.vodafone.ie | kampyleUserSessionsCount | 25  |
| https://www.vodafone.ie | mdigital\_alternative\_uuid | b745-5a4a-7f24-b800-ac06-3110-bc66-adfb |
| https://n.vodafone.ie | \_hjid | 28a2316d-96d0-4f54-8d1d-60bb36344ab3 |
| https://n.vodafone.ie | \_hjRecordingEnabled | TRUE |
| https://n.vodafone.ie | \_hjRecordingLastActivity | 1600951756201 |
| https://n.vodafone.ie | datalayer | {"offerType":"pay as you go phones","addedToBasket":""} |
| https://n.vodafone.ie | hjViewportId | 87b0fe81-dbeb-4107-a6fd-73da7f36d3cb |
| https://n.vodafone.ie | s\_pec |     |

How To Clear Local Storage  

*   Open the Google Chrome Console by pressing F12 key
    
*   .Select “Application” in the console’s top menu
    
*   Select “Local Storage” in the console’s left menu
    
*   ..Right click your site(s) and click clear to delete the local storage.

Want To Change Your Privacy Settings?
-------------------------------------

You can change your privacy settings by logging into My Vodafone and going to 'Manage my settings'. If you have any difficulties you can call us at 1800 200 234 and we will help with any changes you wish to make.

### Assisting law enforcement

Vodafone has to respond to government's legal demands for customer data. You can read more about the legal powers to access customer communications.

### To report a data breach

If you think there is a data breach please submit the details

Frequently asked questions
--------------------------

### Why do I need to answer personal questions every time I call Vodafone?

Each time you contact Vodafone you may be asked a number of security questions to confirm your identity.

This practice works in the interest of your security, ensuring that another person cannot gain access to your account and make changes without your permission.

It is also helpful to our customer service representatives in checking that the account details are accurate and up to date.

### Does Vodafone share my personal data with other companies?

Yes, Vodafone will share your personal data with a number of third party companies who are acting on our behalf to provide a service to you (for example, if you order a new phone, your order will be dispatched to you by our order fulfilment partner).

Vodafone will ensure that the appropriate contractual and security arrangements are in place.

### Do I need to give consent for my phone call to be recorded?

Vodafone record some calls for quality and training purposes, ensuring that we are able to train our staff to handle your queries and offer a best in class service. You will be notified each time you are in contact with us that the call may be recorded for this purpose.

We do not ask for your consent as we have a legitimate business interest in recording calls for quality and training purposes. If you are not happy with a call being recorded, you can end the call at any time. Please note that all recorded calls are deleted within 90 days.

### Can I record my phone call to Vodafone?

By recording your phone call with Vodafone, you will be collecting the personal data of the employee that you are speaking to and will need to notify them that the call is being recorded.

The employee will have the right (as an individual) to object to your recording of the phone call and may choose not to continue with the call.

### Some of Vodafone’s call centres are outside of the EU. Is this legal and is my personal data protected?

Vodafone Ireland is part of the Vodafone Group and we use some services provided to us by other Vodafone companies for performing certain tasks (for example, customer care, administrative functions, and roaming services).

As a result, other Vodafone companies will have access to the personal data that is held by Vodafone Ireland to allow them to complete these tasks.

Vodafone Group ensures that all Vodafone companies maintain the same privacy commitment and that appropriate safeguards are in place. We also maintain intercompany agreements containing the appropriate EU contractual clauses to ensure that your data is protected.

### How do I give my permission to have my personal data shared with other companies?

Sometimes Vodafone will use a third party company to perform certain activities on our behalf.

If these activities are required in order to provide the service (example printing and posting your bill), then we have a legitimate business interest and do not require your permission.

If Vodafone is sharing personal data for any purpose where consent is required, we will ensure to respect your preferences.

### I am receiving unwanted communications from Vodafone about new products and services. How can I stop this?

Vodafone provide a number of choices relating to how your data is used, specifically for marketing, analysis and profiling.

Please visit your My Vodafone account or call 1800 200 234 if you want to check or change your preferences.

### I am receiving communications from Vodafone but am not a Vodafone customer. What should I do?

If you are not a Vodafone customer, please contact us at 01 2037000 or at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to report any unwanted communications that you have received.

We may need to collect some information from you in order to investigate this, (for example, we may ask for your email address and information on the content of the email received).

### How can I get a copy of my personal data?

You can request a copy of your personal data through your online account, or by contacting Vodafone by phone or in store.

You will receive a response within one month of receipt of your request.

### Can I get a copy of a call recording?

Vodafone record some calls for quality and training purposes. Not all calls are recorded and the person with whom you speak will not be able to confirm if the call is being recorded at the time of the call.

Our sales centres record all calls which will be retained for 24 months from the date of the call for the purpose of recording the details of your contract.

You can request a copy of the call record by making a subject data request in My Vodafone.

### What is included in a subject access request?

We will include any personal data that relates to or identifies you. This will include your personal details and may include, for example, details of account notes, call recordings, live chat scripts, etc.

Please let us know if there is anything in particular that you are looking for in order to speed up your request. This can be done through your account in My Vodafone.

### I did not receive all of my personal data from Vodafone. What can I do?

If you feel that you did not receive all the personal data that you expected, please refer to the Privacy Statement where you will find an overview of our data retention schedule giving details of the length of time we retain different types of personal data.

Please contact us if you have any queries about the personal data you have received.

If you are not satisfied, you have the right to complain to the Data Protection Officer at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

### I want to have all of my personal data deleted under the right to be forgotten

If you have an active account with Vodafone, we will be unable to delete your personal data. Vodafone only collect personal data that is necessary to provide you with the service you have requested and to manage your account. We have controls in place to ensure that data is deleted when it is no longer required for the purpose for which it was collected.

While we need to collect and store your personal data in order to manage your account, we may also use this data for analysis of how you use our products and services, and to send you tailored special offers based on your data. You have choices as to how we use your personal data for these purposes and can change your mind at any time. Your preferences can be changed through on your My Vodafone profile, through the settings on our app or by calling 1800 200 234.

If you decide to cease your service, we will retain your personal data for a reasonable period to allow us to answer any queries you might have after you close your account. We may need to extend this period if we require your data for other purposes, such as recovering any outstanding balances.

You can request to have your personal data deleted through your online account, or by contacting Vodafone by phone or in store. If you do not have an active account, or if you wish to make a request regarding specific information that you would like us to delete please email us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

You will receive a response within one month of receipt of your request.

### How can I have my personal data corrected or rectified?

You can update your contact information (address, email etc.) using your My Vodafone online account.

If you become aware that Vodafone may have other information that is incorrect or outdated relating to you, you can submit a request to have this rectified by emailing us at [\[email protected\]](https://n.vodafone.ie/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

You will receive a notification of completion of your request within 30 days.

### What will I receive if I submit a data portability request?

A data portability request will provide you with an electronic file containing the personal data that you have provided to Vodafone.

This will include basic information such as name, address, email address, phone number.

### I need information on text messages I have sent and received

We don’t keep a record of the content of any messages you send.

### I need access to my phone records. Do I need to send a data access request?

You may send a data access request to obtain copies of your call records, however, this information is also available for you to download from your My Vodafone online account.

If you do send a data access request for call records, you will receive copies of the call details section of your monthly bill.

Pay as you go customers will receive a document with records of calls including time and date, and number dialled.

### I need information on calls and texts I made and received

Call records will be available for 6 months from the date of the event to allow you to analyse and, if necessary, query your bill. This will contain outgoing usage details only.

### I need information on my incoming calls?

Vodafone does not have information on incoming calls

### Can you see my location when I make a call?

Network location data will be collected each time you make a call. This information tells us which mobile phone cell site you connected to. This information will be used to enable us to investigate network issues and will not be disclosed except in any case where disclosure is by legal obligation.

### Can I get a copy of my contract?

Copies of consumer bill pay contracts are retained for 24 months. If you agreed or renewed your contract within the last 24 months, please contact Vodafone to provide you with a copy.

### I do not want Vodafone to location data via the My Vodafone App, do I need to disable location settings for all apps I use to prevent this?

Most handsets will have a quick access menu where location services will be disabled for all functions and features on the device. If you want to disable location setting for one app only, select the option for app permissions.
